[Music]
foreign
thank you
[Music]
shopping
hello everybody good evening good day I
hope you're doing wonderfully well and
welcome to this special World Cup
episode of the Oscar budget show
uh so
I have a screen over here right here on
which the World Cup match will be
telecast live I will watch it in the
and while the match is on I'll I I may
take some questions maybe from the live
chat yes and afterwards I will also take
questions that you've asked in the
comments
uh but before we do any of that and I
think the word the match is still about
30 minutes away so let me see who all is
there with us as always I can see
Vladimir Biden
Ramesh
tiwari Summer Afternoon my Lord sheetal
manohari Priya Alpha srishta Rahul Singh
ronak manmat Martian malhar
foreign
um who else lots of people
Vladimir Putin always good to see Mr
Putin
Tamil ketan Priyanka
King Kong
[Laughter]
foreign
and lots and lots of other people thank
you all for being on this telecast with
me Tejas somnath harsh Albert Davis
fatty just ate Siddhartha
Sachin shura
so uh subject 93 and lots of people so
yeah thank you all for being on this day
on this live broadcast telecast while a
World Cup match is on I really
appreciate that
uh so yeah it's still about 30 minutes
to go so let's take some questions if
you have questions ask me and I'll also
take some questions from in
from the comments that you have asked
let's talk let's take a question about
football
oh my
um
and Alejandro Hernandez
so talk about Indian football why did
football fail in India and so on why did
should a should the all India Football
Federation be blamed for football
failure of India or should the people be
blamed of course
I love football and I believe that if I
had been born in another country I would
have been a footballer and Sumit says
football is popular in regions like
Kerala West Bengal Etc compared to other
places is temperature the main reason
that football is not oral popular
so uh Indian football so Indian football
I think football is very popular in
India
Indian football I mean football isn't
popular in India for a very long time I
mean India had qualified for the 1950
World Cup yeah in India had a history of
doing well in the Olympics as well in
the 1952 Olympics I'm not sure how well
it did but in the 56 the Indian football
team reached the semi-finals of the
Olympics yeah at some point in time they
even beat I think they drew with France
or beat France so India had a good
football team in the past
we have had a good football tradition
and uh so why did football fail India in
India it's like if you can ask the same
question about hockey yeah India used to
be the hockey superpower yeah India has
more Olympic goals in hockey than any
other Nation
and uh but it all went downhill from the
1950s and 1960s onwards so that's all
about the mismanagement of India by by
the people in power yeah
uh no investment no no focus on Sports
for any sport to succeed you need to
invest in that sport you have to create
the infrastructure the coaching system
the the supports the support system yeah
and people need to have a certain level
of prosperity to be able to afford to
play sports yeah in the case of hockey
you need certain equipment you need
specialized grounds in the past it used
to be just grass now it's AstroTurf yeah
we also need equipment Acoustics uh the
balls the the protective equipment that
vocabulously people need to wear and all
that and
and as we know the Hockey Federation has
kind of ruined the sport in India and so
similarly I would say that's something
that also happened with football India
had a very good football team I mean if
you reach the Olympic semi-finals it
means that you have a certain quality
yeah
um and the aiff refused to send the
Indian team to the 1950 World Cup can
you believe it India had qualified I
think they qualified by default or
whatever but India had qualified for the
1950 World Cup and the Indian Football
Federation kept on Dilly dallying and
dragging its feet and waiting until the
until it was too late and then they said
and FIFA I believe had uh agreed to put
up most of the expense expenses for the
Indian football team they travel to to
was it in Brazil Argentina somewhere
there the World Cup so to travel there
the FIFA was willing to you know pay
most of the field of the money you know
give the money to to aiff and yet the
Indian Football Federation refused for
whatever reason to send the team for the
World Cup they they I think one of the
reasons they gave is that we want to
focus on the Olympics or the Olympics
are more important and more prestigious
what nonsense
so yeah so India lost a golden chance to
participate in the World Cup we had a
good team at the time yeah we had a good
team so why did football fail it's
because of mismanagement it's because of
of I mean
the way the Federation has kind of
neglected the sport very similar to what
happened happened with hockey
hockey obviously is not a global sport
so India still does well but yeah India
could be number one in the world in
hockey if you just invest
um
football of course you will see kids
playing football all over the country
you don't need I mean Cricket obviously
is more popular in India than football
it's because it's all over the media
it's all it's because it's become it's
it's been made it's been elevated to the
most to the highest profile in all the
sports in India if you were to provide
the same kind of coverage let's say
kabaddi then kabaddi in a decade will
become the most popular sport in India
it's all about the exposure on media and
the coverage on media
and and for a sport like kabaddi or
football you don't need much equipment
for football you just need a ball that's
all you need you can wear your regular
sneakers or whatever you know at the
lower the amateur level you don't need
to wear the the specialized football
boots and even those are not that
expensive so compared to Cricket in
which you need cricket bats you need
gloves you need various other protective
equipment you need balls which are quite
expensive you need stumps you need a
specialized ground and all that compared
to that football is so much I mean you
don't need much money to play football
so football should actually be a more
popular sport in India from that
perspective and yet because because the
media only focuses on Cricket that's why
everybody wants to play cricket because
they feel it's more glamorous and
there's more and obviously if you become
a successful cricketer there is more
money in that there's a we do have a
football league in India the ISL or
whatever and there are some other
competitions tournaments that happen but
you don't earn much money from that even
as a professional footballer you don't
make much money in India and the Indian
footballers for whatever reason I have
not been able to break out of the
country and play in foreign leagues
because because there is not much
exposure of the Indian leagues to to
other countries and all that
so I think it's all about mismanagement
uh is it about uh temperature or
anything no uh actually for it's it's uh
nicer to play any sport when the
temperatures are lower
so from that perspective I think
football should be more popular in
Northern India where the temperatures
are on average lower than
places in Southern India and yet you
will find that football is popular in in
Kerala obviously in Southern India and
uh in the northeast of India the Far
East of India Manipur especially is a
Powerhouse and football manipuri is a
footballing
superpower in within India yeah
um and even West Bengal has a very old
long tradition very glorious tradition
of football they have these teams called
Mohan Bagan and uh
and muhammadan sporting East Bengal yeah
all these teams they have a very good
tradition
um and I think football
I'm sure it's popular everywhere else
also but we don't get any very we don't
get to see it
um so what needs to happen is we need
more investment in football yeah there
is this ISL you know which is kind of
like the the Indian Super League they
call it for football I think a proper
professional League should be eight nine
months long it should not be a one month
tournament or two month tournament like
the IPL is played if you want I mean it
makes a lot of money the IPL makes a lot
of money but it's not in my opinion a
very serious sporting League a proper
League which truly develops the sport
from the Grassroots upwards a proper
leak should be the season should last
eight or nine months and there should be
a three or four month of the or you know
recovery period that's how it goes if
you look at any other uh Nation if you
look at this area in in Italy if you
look at how the Brazilians have their
league
if you look at the PSL the the
Premier Football League the Premier
League in England they have I mean it's
I think the the season lasts eight or
nine months it's an extended drawn out
thing so that's how you do it that's how
it's supposed to be done and you need to
have various uh tiers you know the top
tier
and then relegation to a lower tier
there should be two three tiers and all
that so it should be a very properly
structured thing and obviously the
Indian Football Federation has not
bothered to do any of that yeah so
football languishes and that's the
reason why football hasn't become a big
thing in India I think if you start if
you if the aif get get their act
together they structure a league
properly yeah and the right amount of
money is thrown in you don't need money
from the government bring in private
investors yeah you do it properly you
package it properly you bring in there's
a lot of money in India yeah so you do
it properly within 10 years India can
become a genuine super genuine football
power at least at the Asian level you
have to start with Asia and then go to
the World level so I don't think there's
any dearth of talent or anything there's
this myth that makes that is prevalent
in the minds of Indian people that
Indians are not athletic Indians aren't
strong what absolute nonsense how did
India do so well in hockey in football
in the past yeah even in cricket we used
to be told that Indians can't Bowl fast
Indians should Bowl spin but our the
same the people the same deer pakistanis
they can bowl fast then they should tell
us that no it's because they eat meat
and Indians don't eat meat I'm sorry
Indians also there are lots of Indians
who eat meat and today if you look at I
mean yeah fast bowling right I mean look
at the fast bowling attack of India and
Pakistan today I think in 2020 India had
the most dangerous and scariest fast
bowling attack in the world even even
scarier than the Australians I mean we
beat Australia twice on their home soil
using our fast forward so you know all
these these are all myths that have been
constructed to make Indians feel
inferior that's not the case look at our
weight lifters look at our wrestlers now
we are becoming
at least uh reasonably good power in the
Olympics when it comes to wrestling and
weight lifting even even our girls are
doing so very well yeah
and so so it's all about money it's all
about investment there isn't I mean if
you look at India the people of India
physically we are we are taller and
stronger than most people in Asia I mean
compared to the Chinese the Koreans the
Japanese Indians are taller and stronger
look at the the videos that come out
from the Lac and see on average you have
a bunch of Chinese soldiers and a bunch
of Indian soldiers look just take a look
who looks stronger taller fitter
so please disabuse yourselves of the
these these limiting beliefs that
Indians are you know not strong not
athletic Indians can do anything yeah
so um that's the deal you know
uh it's not the people of India who
should be blamed what are the people to
do
what are the people to do
people want to play football and people
play football kids play football
everywhere especially when a big
tournament is on you'll see kids playing
football all over the place in every
street corner
the people want to play football and
there'll be a lot of talent if only it
is you know if it is nurtured and
invested in you'll find a lot of talent
the student all over the country I think
there's enough talent in the country to
have 10 world-class football teams not
just one
yeah a small tiny State like Manipur
produces incredibly good footballers
and they have they have had the sporting
culture you know this culture of you
know Sports
so that sort of thing could be
inculcated elsewhere also and with so
little investment in in the Far East of
Indian in the Northeast there's even
less investment
than in other parts of India and yet
Manipur does well Manipur produces so
many footballers who play for various uh
clubs and leagues all over India
so there is Talent there's Talent
everywhere so it's not the people who of
India who are to be blamed it's the
system that's to be blamed
so yeah that's uh that's the answer to
this question football yeah that's why
it has failed but I think if the proper
system is set up in the proper kind of
infrastructure is created investment is
done then within a decade India could be
a power a footballing power it's just
waiting to happen
who is your favorite footballer of all
time well I don't have one favorite
footballer right I've liked many
footballers admired many footballers so
I I have not seen people like Pele Etc
play so I don't know much about that
I've seen some footage of Pele playing
obviously it was a great footballer he's
considered to be one of the greatest of
all time if not the greatest of all time
but I have never seen him play so I
don't know
so so from the I'll talk about the ones
I have seen playing and one of the first
footballers that captured my imagination
was Diego Maradona yeah tremendously
gifted uh footballer
incredible incredible genius level
talent in football he could do things
nobody else could do he could even get
away with scoring a goal with his hand
which he didn't did in 1986 against the
hapless Englishmen well deserved well
played sir he obviously passed away some
some time ago but yeah so one of the
first footballers who who I liked a lot
was Diego Armando Maradona who else did
I like
from the 1990s the first World Cup I
kind of watched was the it was Italian
it the World Cup in Italy in 1990. so
from that time I liked Diego Maradona I
liked Claudio Khadija who was also in
the Argentina team
kanija was a very
was a guy with a lot of speed
you can think of him as as an
Argentinian mbappe mbappe is known for
his incredible bursts of acceleration
right nobody can catch up with him he
runs that fast so Claudio canija was
like that so I like kanija I liked
obviously Maradona uh from that time I
liked Marco van basten
and uh Frank reichardt the three
Dutchmen who played for AC Milan
um who else did I like
so from that yeah and obviously I liked
uh Eric Cantona wonderful player French
player who played mostly for Manchester
United wonderful player he was he's of
Indian origin by the way Romani French
Romani
um very Mercury Mercurial gifted player
very interesting person he's now an
actor he's an actor now very interesting
guy uh you can I think there's a couple
of one or two Series in which he has
acted which is on Netflix
so yeah Continental was great I really
admired the way he played uh who else
I uh among more recent players I
obviously admire Messi
and uh who else but I also admire the
way Cristiano Ronaldo plays I don't like
him as a person he's very selfish
self-centered egoistic not a good I
don't like him as a person
I may be wrong it's my opinion but yeah
as a player you got to admire his work
work ethic and his style of play and his
record of playing at the highest level
for so many years you've got to admire
that so Cristiano Ronaldo yes Messi
obviously he is the likely success of
the successor to Diego Maradona once
Messi retires will be able to look at
him you know from from more holistic
perspective but yes he is Argentina's
successor so Diego Maradona he is also
somebody who has played performed for so
many years and uh maybe that's why I am
kind of inclined to support Argentina
because this may be misses this is most
likely message last World Cup it would
be nice to see him retire with the World
Cup yeah
so yeah and and who else uh zidane I
like zidane zidane was a great great
player he turned he he carried France in
the 1998 World Cup
Indians for some reason support Brazil a
lot yeah I remember in the I watched the
1998 World Cup final live I was in a
hostile hostel room hostel Auditorium
with a whole bunch of students and it
was me and a boy from Iran the two of us
were supporting France everybody else
was supporting Brazil and by World by by
half time everybody was quiet because
zidane had scored two headers it was two
zero by halftime France won 3-0 I think
at the end of the day so that was a good
World Cup so I liked zidane I liked
what was his name
uh
so that guy played for Manchester United
very good player I also liked Theory Ori
of France who played for Arsenal so I
have had I don't have one single
footballer who I hold above everybody
else if you want to if you want me to
give just one name it may be perhaps
Diego Maradona but he did not perform at
the highest level for a very long period
of time at least
in a way I saw it he obviously played
for uh Napoleon I believe in Italy and
they they loved him very much there they
loved him so much that when Argentina
played Italy in
the 1990 World Cup I think it was in
Nepali was it and the people of the city
came out and supported Argentina just
because of one guy Maradona and I think
Italy ended up losing that match
if I'm not mistaken it was in Napoli
Naples
Napoleon most likely
yeah so
yeah it's that's interesting isn't it
so uh maybe if you want to ask me just
one person maybe it would be Diego
Armando Maradona but I have admired lots
of footballers I've been I'm a big
Sports opinion Aficionado I've never
played football except at school level
you know as a kid that is just that
sounds serious
so yeah uh I I usually don't speak about
sports but I I've been a big Sports
fanatic not fanatic but Sports buff yeah
I really enjoy sport I've followed sport
I watched the Olympics track and field I
even played Cricket at a certain level
because in India there's no other option
I even if you want to play football
nobody wants to play football so you you
can if you can't beat them you're gonna
join them so then I played Cricket in
the I used to be a bowler of various
kinds
so yeah
um
so yeah that's about my favorite
footballer of all time now let's take
some questions from the live chat I'm
sure people are saying lots of things
neapolitan pizza I'm sure neapolitan
pizza is wonderful yes
uh let's remove this yes
um
who will win prediction well
I obviously my team isn't playing India
isn't playing so from that perspective
I'm a little bit uh neutral I'll I have
in the past supported France in the 1998
World Cup I supported France
um so yeah when your team isn't involved
you tend to support some other team for
whatever reason now if you uh
so in in the 1990 World Cup final I
supported Argentina because I wanted
Maradona to win one more World Cup and
obviously uh that did not go as I wanted
it to go uh because Germany won that
World Cup final 1-0 the it was it was a
penalty you know a questionable penalty
that was given to Germany after 80
minutes
uh I think it was uh Andreas Brahma who
was fouled apparently and the penalty
was taken by Rudy Waller if I'm not
mistaken and lothar Matthias was the
captain of Germany
so who will win I I would like to see
Argentina win just for Messi because I
like the guy I also like France they
were good players and if France wins
then they will be one of the only the
third team if I'm not mistaken to retain
the World Cup title uh
I think it was in the 1930s almost a
century ago that Italy won two
consecutive titles World Cup titles and
then I believe Brazil also in the 60s
and 70s won two consecutive World Cup
titles and it's not happened ever since
so if France win today then they'll be
the third team to to successfully defend
their World Cup title if they lose then
Argentina becomes the a three-time
winner I don't think then I have won two
World Cups before 78 and 86 86 was all
on the back of Diego Maradona
so yeah
Uruguay
has Uruguay defended the championship I
think Uruguay has won two if I'm not
mistaken long time ago uh they aren't uh
a major force today
uh
right so that's how it is Argentina will
win let's see Sunil chatri takes
Ronaldo's Sunil shatri is a wonderful
player uh he even played for a bit I
think in North America in the U.S and I
think he performed quite well I've seen
some footage of Sunil chetri playing
in some match in North America in the
U.S and he he played very competently
very well he clearly was the world class
level but unfortunately because of the
system he could never break out of India
and yeah
wonderful player
so we've had really good players in
India and uh there are many other good
players
uh my favorite sport my favorite sport
uh I I played Cricket it's not quite my
favorite sport I I don't have one single
favorite sport I like I like contact
Sports I like to watch Boxing I like to
watch MMA I like wrestling wrestling is
fun yeah weightlifting is fun
in the yeah even tennis I used to watch
in the past nowadays I don't watch
Tennis anymore it's become really I
don't even know who are the top players
these days in the past you had good
players uh we still have
Nadal and uh Joker right Djokovic
Federer retired but apart from these
people I don't know who who else is
there
so yeah you know usable boxing yeah
boxing is a good sport MMA nowadays is
more exciting it's a more 360 degree
contact sport you know boxing has very
it's only about the fists you can't use
any other part of the body in MMA you
can use essentially any part of the body
and use any technique you want including
wrestling techniques and punching
techniques and kissing techniques and
grappling in Jiu Jitsu and whatnot MMA
is fun I I enjoy watching the I enjoy
watching MMA mixed martial arts who's my
most favorite cricketer of all time
well um I used to be a bowler
uh who would be my I once again I would
not have one single favorite trigger I
think the most uh the scariest bowler
I've seen was Jeff Thompson you all may
not even have heard of it Go to YouTube
and search for Jeff Thompson's bowling
footage my God it was frightening he
consistently bowled above 160 kilometers
per hour you know
he consistently bowled above 100 miles
per hour
and Brett Brett Lee and all they they
were nothing compared to him so yeah
Thompson Jeff Thompson was a frightful
bowler frightfully scary bowler
and obviously uh if you talk about fast
bowling curtly Ambrose it was never the
fastest bowler but good God it was
brilliant it was like a machine bowling
machine so yeah currently Ambrose uh
Shane Warne yeah for sure Shane Warne
um Anil kumble was very frustrating
especially in one day matches every
Overhill Bowl One bad ball
he's one of the greats among batsmen
beverages I'm sure most of you have not
seen him but he was great Richards was
great
um among Indian players maybe lakshman
VVS lakshman
um I like srinath even though he was
very unfortunate a lot of time but he
was once the in the 1999 World Cup was
the fastest bowler in the world without
a doubt really fast even faster than in
99 in that World Cup in that one World
Cup
um among today's cricketers who do I
like
in the Indian team I like I like bumrah
but I don't know where he is right now I
like a really hard-working guy with
limited Talent he's become one of the
best
all around us in the world he's gonna be
remembered as one of the best of all
time Rahul dravid obviously
am I missing somebody I'm sure people
will not be happy with some omissions
that's hard yes the dhoni for sure Ms
dhoni for sure great player
um King of Swing you know Jimmy Anderson
I really like his bowling action it's
it's a pleasure to watch him Bowl very
nice bowling action as a person I don't
like him very much he's kind of a
yes yes he's not no longer that good but
there was a time when he was really
really good Cooley yes uh any memories
from 83 I did not I don't have any
memory of 83 but I did not watch the
World Cup or or anything so yeah I don't
have any memories of 83 Kapil there was
great couple that was great for sure he
was one of the great Bowlers a great
all-rounders uh he could have been a
much he could have achieved much more as
a batsman but that's okay that's how it
goes
there was great uh
there was this guy called prabhakar he
did not really perform if you look at
his record it's kind of average but he
was a very interesting bowler you know
and so on
I'm sure I've missed out a lot of people
but uh
yeah so
I I had lots of uh players I liked
watching
injured yes Burma is injured any South
African player I liked funny de Villiers
I'm sure nobody remembers funny de
Villiers he was a bowler
I first saw him in 93 or so the first
time I saw him he was bowling at a black
eye for some reason he had a black guy a
funny de Villiers very very interesting
character in a good bowler so I liked
funny the videos I do not like Donald as
a person Aaron Donald but it was a joy
to watch when he was not bowling against
India Indians were very bad at playing
fast bowling in those days you bold fast
Indians will get out that's how it goes
there was this match in Durban I believe
in India in India
India was all out for 66 you know in I
think half the runs were scored by Rahul
dravid
and it was not some extreme fast bowling
bowling or anything it was just poor
batting
so yeah South African players I would
say funny the Villiers I liked uh what
was his name Brian MacMillan all-rounder
he was good Donald was good
um
ABD Villiers obviously was good uh Sean
Pollock was good for a while
all rounder these days I like that guy
Marco Janssen the left arm bowler
uh yeah he's good these days
uh Gibbs was good Gibbs Herschel Gibbs
uh yeah they had good players
what about mbappe will he be the next
Messi we will see we will see if he will
be the next messy he's clearly extremely
talented he has this speed the
acceleration like like nobody else has
you know very talented he's still very
young I can see the players are about to
kick off now the the World Cup final is
about to start Griezmann has the ball I
think France has won the toss if they're
gonna start off
it's about to start yeah
um
you want a podcast with Praveen Mohan
I'll try and reach out to him
let's see
where's this question I saw a question
which disappeared
Muhammad Ali or Mike Tyson well I
haven't really seen Muhammad Ali play a
box I've seen some old footage he
clearly was one of obviously one of the
greats one of the very greats I I think
many people consider he took the
greatest boxer of all time but I have
seen Mike Tyson boxing my god there was
nobody's carrier than Mike Tyson he was
just about six six feet tall six one he
was one of the smallest heavyweights of
all time oh my God Mike Tyson was
ferocious scary
scary knockout power it would knock you
out within seconds you know that's how
he was eventually age catches up with
you and then he lost his title and all
that then he had some problems with the
law
and and all that but yes among the
boxers I have seen i i rate Mike Tyson
the highest and the the era in which
Muhammad Ali played it it was not that
physical compared to how it was during
Mike Tyson's time you know it was uh so
if you see Muhammad Ali's physique it's
nowhere as impressive as that of Mike
Tyson so the physique physique also used
to be different in those days but yeah
Muhammad Ali had some great great uh
fights This Record is incredible yes he
fought some really enormous and scary
guys and he defeated them through
strategy through tactics
that's not easy to do when you're
getting punched there's a saying right I
think Mike Tyson said this that you can
come with the best plans in the world
but the moment you're punched in the
face all the plans go out of the window
so it's really impressive that somebody
can stick towards strategy and tactics
and plan a plan B Etc in the midst of a
boxing match a boxing fight 15 rounds or
whatever
so yeah uh it's so very impressive
Muhammad Ali but I have from my
perspective from what I've seen Mike
Tyson I think nobody can match him these
days you have uh Tyson Fury he is a very
interesting character I mean he doesn't
look like a boxer he looks like I mean
he's overweight he's a fat guy like he
himself says and yet he's the champion
he's a world champion right now the
World Heavyweight Champion uh Tyson Fury
very interesting character so now the
World Cup match has started final match
it's two minutes in Argentina has the
ball
Argentina is wearing their traditional
yellow uh sorry blue light blue and
white shirt
and
yes they are attacking Argentina is
attacking right now Messi has the ball
and it's in the Box oh good save good
save so what's the guy's name I think
their new Striker he tried a shot on the
goal it was on target but the but the
goalkeeper the French goalkeeper Lori
Hugo Lori saved it so yeah interesting
start to the match interesting start
Adam Gilchrist yeah yeah he was he was
exciting he was fun to watch it was fun
to watch list some of his innings are
very interesting very hard hitting
batsman very exciting batsman scored
very fast some of his ashes innings are
very interesting fun to watch especially
against England yeah yeah I kind of
liked him yeah
do I like Conor McGregor I think it's
very interesting he's very exciting it's
always fun to watch him he he there is
not a single boring moment when Conor
McGregor is either either talking or
fighting yeah these days he has lost a
few matches his record of late has been
a little patchy he lost to khabib khabib
nurmag the the dagestani Russian uh
fighter so that kind of and then he lost
to what's his name the American guy also
recently I think he suffered a leg
fracture in the middle of the fight
Conor McGregor and now he is back to
training he has put on a lot of muscle
mass so he has gone up I think at least
one weight category
so yeah I I think and and here's this
this walk right which he copied from Mr
McMahon off of the WWE
so yeah he's a very interesting
character there's never a boring moment
when Conor McGregor is is on the screen
either talking or or
or fighting and I think he's also
interesting he's got an entertaining uh
social media presence also
yeah so yeah I kind of like him khabib
is the best I think Habib is one of the
greatest of all time uh in MMA my
personal favorite used to be uh
Fedor
Fedor emilianenko he is from a
generation before but yeah one of the
greatest Fighters I have seen Fedor he
was a heavyweight
uh he was also one of the smaller
heavyweights but good God he could
destroy Fighters so my favorite
personally was feather emilianenko but
khabib obviously is one of the best he
hasn't he never he never even bled
another Argentinian shot on target saved
by the goalkeeper it was an easy save
khabib the thing about him is that in
MMA when you fight most Fighters bleed I
have not seen a single fighter who has
never bled but khabib I have never ever
seen him even shed a drop of blood from
his nose or anywhere else I've never
seen him bleed
and uh yeah I think most of his fights I
think he won all his fights I I'm sure
he's he played more than 30. he fought
more than 30 fights if I'm not mistaken
I'm not sure what the record is more
than 30 fights most likely in MMA in UFC
he won every single fight and he retired
after after uh
after defeating I think just engage you
if I'm not mistaken
yeah so Kabhi clearly is one of the best
of all time
um
Roger Federer uh really really pleasing
to watch the the grace the Elegance with
which he played incredible but also you
could see the hard work that he used to
put in you know it's not enough to have
talent you need to have her you need to
be able to work hard Nadal isn't the
most elegant player the you know the
most pleasing player but you you know he
puts in the hard work Djokovic also but
Federer was the most pleasing to the eye
most elegant tennis player I think I've
ever seen
so yeah I I really used to admire Roger
Federer and uh yeah now he obviously has
retired High Time
because he was not winning of late
uh do I watch chess matches no I don't
have the patience I used to play chess
as a kid then I gave it up because I may
have been good perhaps but I gave it up
because it takes too much time and
watching chess is like watching grass
grow
it's like watching grass growing you
know some just if you watch speed chess
it may be maybe interesting but I've
never really watched the chess match
so yeah I don't watch chess matches 30-0
are you predicting the score
30 0 would be a
would be exceptional
uh have I played kabaddi I think I
played kabaddi a few times when I was a
kid I would have been good because I'm
I'm rather large and I'm rather strong
I've always been physically strong
and yeah in terms of strength I always
had this advantage over most kids in
terms of height in terms of of the
physical strength I was always a strong
kid you know and my grip is rather good
so in in cupboard you need a good grip
you want to uh yeah so
I remember when I played kabaddi a few
times once I caught somebody the guy
could not Escape so yeah a few times I
played kabaddi
um have you ever built muscle Not Just
Fitness or proactively yeah yeah I I had
a good physique before the pandemic then
two years until recently I haven't even
gone back to gym almost two and a half
years yeah so I've kind of lost that
muscle mass and I did a few bouts of
fasting extended fasting I did a 21 day
water fast a 23 day water fast and about
a year ago I did a 14 day water fast you
do that you're gonna lose muscle so
right now I'm I've kind of lost some of
the muscle mass but yes I I really enjoy
lifting weights it's really I mean it's
one of them pleasurable things in life
going to gym and lifting heavy weights
you know so I really enjoy that so uh if
you if you see my
on this channel I have this video in
which I give an introduction to the RN
Invasion Theory it's at a book launch
a book launch a dual a double book
launch by stikanthalagiri and Dr um
General GS bakshi so if you see my
physique there it's it's like rather
large compared to what it is right now
so I I need to get back to Jim and start
lifting weights regularly again I think
in three four months I can most likely
regain that large physique that that is
that is something that's kind of natural
to me so yes I have enjoyed building
muscle it's good fun
so yeah I've done that in the past yeah
who's the greatest athlete of all time
for me maybe using Bolt
maybe using bolt good God that guy was
spectacular yeah
uh how many Olympics did he win I wonder
Usain Bolt
uh he he
the Beijing Olympics one was the 2008
then you had the the
so I think three four Olympics
he was the champion
so I I would say perhaps Usain Bolt is
is the uh
possibly
for me
the greatest athlete of all time can you
can you think of somebody else Michael
Phelps interesting yeah Michael Phelps
is another great champion
uh who also and and then there was
Thorpe yeah yeah but I think Michael
Phelps is a swimmer was better than
Thorpe
thorpo's Australian Phelps was American
maybe Michael Phelps yes
Geo Cinema is buffering good God what is
wrong with this
this is the problem is anybody else I'm
using jio Cinema and it's buffering now
it's dead
that's not a good thing in the middle of
the World Cup
uh
Alexander killerin no I have not heard
of this name
sounds like a Russian name but yeah not
sure so Usain Bolt uh one three times
yes
okay what's my favorite FIFA World Cup
2010 2006 98 2014 2018. I did not I
think 2006 I watched the final
it was Italy versus France wasn't it and
it was the the infamous head bucked
headbutt by Zina zidane on Marco
materazzi Marco madrasi ended up scoring
one goal and then he riled up the United
by saying certain things
and zidane lost his school and he
head-butted him so yeah but that was not
that fun of a World Cup I think my
favorite world cup that I watched was 98
most likely most likely
2018 was in Russia uh France won that
was an interesting World Cup lots of
goals yeah that was also good 2014 was
in Brazil wasn't it and uh
who won the 2014 World Cup I think I
remember
ah Germany won the World Cup they
defeated Brazil 7-1 in I think a
semi-final that was a fun match to watch
about five goals in about 10 minutes
ridiculous incredible
so there have been many good World Cups
20 uh
2014 was interesting 2018 lots of goals
yes France played really really well 98
was good uh I enjoyed that as well so
yeah I don't have one favorite world cup
I enjoyed several World Cups
goalkeeper is injured uh he seems to be
doing okay good good the argentines are
really
playing well in the Box in the
in the French box good
greatest female athlete now that's a
good question greatest female athlete
um
greatest female athlete
or if you talk about
I would say Florence Griffith Joyner but
she is known to have taken performance
enhancing substances most likely and she
died of at a very young age which kind
of happens when you take certain
substances so maybe not her
who else do we know of is a great female
athlete
uh merlinotti was good but she never won
in the Olympics
um maybe Steffi Graf maybe maybe Serena
Williams
some of them come to mind but yeah
good question greatest female athlete
I'm I'm not able to think of anybody
from track and field or or any such
thing
so maybe one of these ladies maybe
Steffi Graf perhaps or Serena Williams
in tennis Perhaps Perhaps good question
interesting question makes me think
uh
DJ
are you talking about Gabriella TV
Usha was one of India's greatest
athletes uh especially female athletes
I'm sure we have many more who will come
up in the future Maria Sharapova was
yeah she won a few grand slams
but I would not call her the greatest of
all
in tennis I I'm not I would not call
Maria Sharapova to be the great to be
the greatest tennis player I've seen for
sure
um
yeah he was he was a great fighter I've
never seen any of his matches live or
anything but yeah he's considered to be
one of the greatest MMA fighters of all
time yeah among the greatest
so yeah I think he's clearly one of the
greatest of all not I would not call him
the greatest of all but one of the
greatest Jose Pierre
um
my views of on Andrew Tate well I
haven't really seen any of his videos as
such I I'm aware of his existence now
because people ask me about him
uh but um
I I know that he's got very
controversial opinions and all but I I
haven't really seen his videos I don't
watch podcasts because it takes too much
time just like watching a chess match
I'm sure there's a lot to learn from
podcasts but I really am so busy these
days so so I don't know so I don't
really know much about Android to give
an answer maybe if I find the time I'll
watch maybe a couple of his podcasts and
then form a more informed opinion you
know yeah
maricom one of the greatest of all time
yeah good good point she I think she's a
five-time world champion in boxing
that's an incredible achievement so yes
clearly I would say her achievements are
greater than that of PT Usha or most
athletes in the world I mean winning a
world championship I think five times
even if it's four times it's incredible
so yes one of the greats one of the
all-time greats worldwide I would say
maricom
yes the Romanian athlete gymnast who who
is now an American citizen she's the
first gymnast in Olympic history to
score a perfect 10. it was in the 70s I
think
yeah so Nadia kawanachi is considered to
be one of the Legends in in gymnastics
Romanian athlete gymnast one of the
greats
um best puller of the ball Rohit Sharma
pointing daunting
taunting
was a natural puller of the ball it was
an instinctive shot for him even for
Rohit Sharma it is but I would consider
pointing to be a better puller of wall
puller and hooker of the ball
um
Margaret Court 64 Grand Slams did she
win 64. that's in that's a superhuman
achievement I think Margaret court is
the
if not the number one most likely the
the person with the highest number of
grand slam wins
Argentina is doing really well boom ah
it went over the goalkeepers
yeah they're they're doing well
Argentina
uh Margaret Court may be one of the
greatest but I've never seen her play so
don't really know much
about her who's my favorite cricketer in
India right now
I really like
old-fashioned cricketer but I really
like him I also like jadeja
um Ashwin I really admire Ashwin I think
Ashwin has been uh kind of treated very
unfairly he was dropped he has been
dropped for so many matches he could
have played especially test matches if
you look at ashwin's record it is better
than the record of Imran Khan better
than the record of vakarian is better
than the record of wasimakram and he's
an all-rounder he's called I think five
test centuries Ashwin is a is one of the
all-time greats and he he must have been
he must have been made to miss at least
20 test matches just because there was
he was benched
uh so I would say
Ashwin oh you're saying about you're
asking about female cricketer and a
female cricketer I I'm
female I I don't really watch that much
female Cricket there's this new girl who
is a bowler what's her what's her name
um radhika something she's a good she
she's a good bowler
thakur radhika thakur
I think that's that's the name then the
current Captain what's her name harleen
core
then there is the smriti Mandana the
left left handed batter we we have good
talent
uh
I I forget the names I don't watch
cricket female Cricket much maybe I may
have watched it briefly but there is
impressive torrent among among our
female players as well
that's a good question yeah so he
I would say that that new girl who bowls
you know the molar she's a very good
player
that's right Julian goswami one of the
all-time greats fast bowler I mean you
know one of the fastest female borrowers
we've ever seen is
and uh Harman preet caught the captain
she's a very very good batter
yes that's right favorite badminton
player
uh obviously I will support PV Sindhu
right um
I think she could not play the the
latest World Championship because of
injury but she was the previous world
champion and she's performed well in the
Olympics too I think we're gonna have
better
players in the future badminton players
India is already becoming a major force
in badminton Whoopsie Daisy ahiru
yeah so the French are now attacking in
the Argentinian um in the box and one
header just went over the goal good good
interesting match
so yeah Julian goes for me favorite
badminton player I would support PV
Sindhu Saina Neville was good Saina
versus China it used to be you know the
only player who could who could
challenge the Chinese
um
apart from that I've not really watched
badminton much I remember I once watched
gopichand win the all India all all
England Championship or something
against a Chinese guy I think his name
was Chen Hong or something
um
Italy Raj I think I've I've heard of her
she was she was really good if I'm not
mistaken
um she must have retired by now yeah
um
what else
axelson lakshasen Lee Chong Lee Chong
Wei was a really good player I think he
still plays if he's not mistake if he's
not retired lindan Linden good good
player
uh yeah yeah these are all good players
uh
yes I know of Amelia
your heart uh she was an aviator a
female aviator who who disappeared
and they've been trying to find the
wreckage of a plane or trying to find
out what happened to her and it's still
a mystery yeah so yes I've heard of the
story
uh
Bryant or Lebron or Curry Steph Curry
LeBron James
Bryant Kobe Bryant I don't really watch
uh basketball much I'm aware of these
people Michael Jordan was one of the
greats
do we have a penalty no we don't have a
penalty
so yeah I don't really watch basketball
that much so I don't really know among
these who would be the best I think uh
Michael Jordan was most likely one of
the greatest of all time if not the
greatest of all time
but I haven't really followed basketball
that much so
so can't say
uh right
um
oh Lee Chong Wei undergone cancer
treatment that's that's unfortunate I
hope he's fine I hope he is doing better
do I watch pro wrestling i i as a kid I
used to watch WWE it used to be called
the WWF in the past a long time ago
I don't watch it anymore it's we know
it's all scripted it's more
entertainment than wrestling so I
haven't watched wrestling in about 20
years you know the WWE
well oh yeah we have a penalty
we have a penalty Messi is about to take
a penalty good god what happened
foreign
let's see what happens messy big big big
pressure on his head
the hopes of an entire nation
are on his shoulders come on Mercy
messy usually takes a very soft you know
very very gentle penalty usually
let's see how he goes this time against
Hugo loris
here we go
sin your mercy you're gonna do it
and he scores are 1-0 up
all right it is Advantage Argentina In
This World Cup final Messi has scored
from the penalty spot
awesome and they're now they're all now
trying to kill him by jumping on top of
him
I hope he survives the Huddle
all right awesome Argentina 1-0 up
but it's it's still 22 minutes in so
it's it's early days in this match in
this match
France are very capable of bouncing back
from this
but you know it it takes a lot of mental
strength to take a penalty it was a soft
penalty as always a very gentle kick
I mean
relatively gentle kick
but yeah he did it
he has done his duty given the first
goal for Argentina good
now let's see how France respond to this
this is going to be interesting
favorite Javelin thrower neerajobra
there used to be this German guy
I forget his name he I think he coached
near Chopra who is the all-time world
record holder 110 meters or so uh in the
in the past javelins used to be lighter
I think now they're heavier so when the
old standards were in play that's when
he threw it about 110 meters or so
that's the that I think that record will
never be broken but in today's world
obviously my favorite German thrower
will be neither jopra our guy yes
um
take my question why do they let
rishabhanth play in most of the matches
when there are several better players I
think Richard
um is one of the
uh see from a batting perspective there
are very few like him he reminds me of
Adam Gilchrist especially in test
matches I mean a guy who is so attacking
you would expect him to play well in
2020s in one day matches but he performs
at the test level which is kind of
paradoxical
you know even virender people expected
he would play really well in in Limited
hours Cricket but he was a great test
match player
so yeah sometimes it's paradoxical I
would say that Richard punt is one of
the best batsmen in the world right now
very attacking batsman he can change the
complexion for match uh in in one
session in test matches yeah
and maybe that's the reason why he is
being favored as an as a wicket keeper
he isn't isn't the best I'm sure there
are better Wicket Keepers in India
compared to Richard pant but are those
Wicket Keepers capable of batting Like
Richard I I'm not sure people talk about
Sanju Samson I'm I have not seen much of
him and rishabhand is a young guy I
think one typically wants to invest in
one player especially at the Test match
level like the Australians once they
found Guild quest they did not consider
any other player any other Wicket keeper
yes when they had Healy they stuck to
Healy
stability for India
was one of one of the greatest Wicket
Keepers too but a great batsman as well
so I think you got to pick one player
stick to the person give that person the
chance and I think Richard Pond is a
world-class player especially in test
matches so maybe that is the is the
logic
that that's the the reasoning behind
picking him you keep on picking lots of
players especially the Test match level
there is no continuity and there is uh
a kind of instability you want to have a
more or less subtle team at least some
key players should be should have some
longevity
so maybe that's the reason why I'm sure
there are many other players so if you
can give some names it will be
interesting to see that
Coco underrated uh you know
as a kid I've
I think I've played Coco once or twice I
always I may be completely wrong here
but I always saw it as a girls game a
girl's sport because girls used to play
it all the time
all right oopsie Daisy
French free kick and French corner now I
suppose yeah so I always saw Coco as a
girls sport I may be completely long I'm
sure boys men also play it
it's it's a if you were to ask me which
is my favorite Indian sport I would 100
say kabaddi kabaddi is is more exciting
it's it's faster it's a contact sport
you need to have some bronze some
physical strength and also some finesse
some technique that is strategy and all
but yeah
Coco I'm sure it's very popular among
among lots of people
um but nowadays I don't know where the
sport is
it's definitely not telecast anywhere
I'm sure India has lots of indigenous
sports that are kind of being
marginalized right now and Coco is one
that was quite popular I don't know how
it is now
all right
um my favorite chess player
well if you
maybe maybe Gary Kasparov
uh definitely one of one of the people I
admire is vishwanathan Anand
Bobby Fischer I heard was a chess genius
the American who gave up who renounced
his American citizenship yeah so
yeah
why does no one talk about Northeast
India I think I spent some time just a
few minutes ago talking about Northeast
India Manipur is is within India one of
the one of the uh football superpowers
yeah
and in the Northeast
far east of India there's a lot of
football talent and football is is
extremely big
over there
so yeah
and and the Northeast the Far East of
India is is beautiful wonderful people
so what a wonderful diversity of
different kinds of traditions and
cultures beautiful indigenous culture
and so on so it's a wonderful place I
think the Northeast needs to be promoted
it's our gateway to uh to Southeast Asia
uh there is so much potential for
development for tourism and other things
over there so I I hope to see a very
bright future very soon
for the various States in what we call
Northeast India it's actually the Far
East of India
don't you read Brazilian football I
think Brazilian football is wonderful
they have a great tradition of football
uh some really incredibly great
footballers like obviously like Pele
people talk about Pele but also Ronaldo
the original Ronaldo today we have
Cristiano Ronaldo but we had a Ronaldo
before him
uh so that guy Ronaldo the one who
played in the 2002 World Cup final and
he won the final that guy was brilliant
and Ronaldinho Ronaldinho was was
brilliant one of the Geniuses Roberto
Carlos have you seen the free kick
everyone talks about the free kick
Roberto Carlos we had kafu we had
many other players
I don't I'm not a huge fan of Neymar but
yeah I do rate Brazilian football so
they have a wonderful football setup
great football in Tradition it's part of
their DNA essentially yeah
and and Brazil tells you you don't have
to be huge physically to play great
football and to be Champions the
Brazilian players are average height
average physique but they are
wonderfully gifted I mean they play good
great football so yeah I I am fond of
Brazilian football for sure
do I follow climbing I am aware of
climbing I don't really follow it but
it's it's a good fun sport to watch rock
climbing either on an artificial wall
with those artificial things or actual
climbing you know Mountaineering
uh yeah and one of the greatest climbers
of all time is is an american guy of
Indian origin his dad was is Indian
Sharma his surname Sharma Chris Sharma
or something like that he's one of the
one of the greatest climbers of all time
yes
um
best mind game maybe chess maybe chess
is the best mind game perhaps
Carlson or casparov I think Carlson
could end up being greater than Kasparov
perhaps uh these guys are from different
eras Kasparov was from the 1980s 70s and
80s
um and 90s as well
he retired in the 90s but uh when
Kasparov was a young and upcoming
upcoming player I think Anatoly karpov
was the world champion and Casper of
beat karpov in a legendary world
championship match you know the first
it it was adjourned and canceled once
I think they played I don't know 30 40
games all were draws first carpo first
won three or four games then Kasparov
was a very attacking player he changed
his strategy completely he he adopted a
completely defensive game and he
essentially learned started learning
from karpo so karpov became kasperov's
teacher there were this series of draws
I don't know 20 30 40 draws the both the
players became completely exhausted
emaciated and they this world
championship had to be adjourned and
then it was played again and then Casper
of one so yeah that was
a legendary World Cup uh World
Championship
match
so Kasparov has done things that uh
Carlson most likely still hasn't been
able to emulate but maybe by the time
Carlson is done Magnus Carlson maybe he
may be the greatest fault of all time
Perhaps Perhaps
what do I think of American football I
don't really follow American football I
think it's a very dangerous game they
have to play wearing helmets and all and
there are all these studies that have
come out that demonstrate that that all
these players that suffer lots of brain
damage and all that so I think it's a
dangerous game I think it's a dangerous
game and just for people's entertainment
you should not get you know players hurt
so it's like the the gladiatorial sport
which you had in in ancient Rome kill
people for for the Public's
entertainment I think American football
maybe is is too violent of a sport maybe
there's too much brain brain damage
a player who plays for a number of years
typically will have demonstrable brain
damage you know lots of concussions lots
of head injuries I am sure a similar
situation may also exist in rugby
so I don't really follow American
football I think it's a really violent
game it may be entertaining perhaps but
and it's it's I believe quite similar in
some ways to to to rugby yeah
some of the older great players in chess
I I don't I'm not really very um
familiar with their achievements and all
certainly a
H I've heard the names yeah
uh no no I I refuse to be drawn into con
into into controversies I I shall
Diplomat I shall be diplomatic and not
answer this question
uh sorry no no no I'm not going there
horse races I I I've never watched horse
racing I've never been interested in
that so
I think horse racing is all about
gambling more or less yeah
so not sure
what about F1 Cena Leclerc and Indian
not sure about Leclerc but Cena Sena was
one of the greatsena the Brazilian there
was a time when it was the French guy
who's the French guy Cena versus
I I forget the French guy's name there
was this rivalry between Senna and uh
Michelle Prost was it I think his name
was Michelle Prost yeah these two guys
had a great rivalry and Cena was
brilliant but unfortunately lost his
life very early
1994 Imola if I'm not mistaken
Senna died in a car crash in that uh
F1 race I think it was in 1994 in Imola
if I am not mistaken so yeah Cena was
great it was a great great uh
F1 driver
ah where did football originate so the
modern game of football association
football I think it originates in in
England
but a
obviously there are many nations many
many cultures in the world that have
played various kinds of ball games
including uh playing with the feet for
instance in in ancient America in the
ancient Americas in mesoamerica
there was this this football kind of
game you know they used to play and uh
the winner would have his life sacrifice
that's how it used to be that's what is
that's what historians say you know it
was a privilege to win and then
sacrifice oh God
two zero two zero yes two zero Angel Di
Maria he's a great player Angel Di Maria
fantastic 2-0 Argentina are up
this is beginning to become a disaster
for France difficult for them to come
back from this but we have seen teams
come back from 2-0 Down In This World
Cup itself
uh Argentina number 2-0 up against the
Dutch and the Dutch managed to come back
to 2-2 they obviously lost afterwards
but yeah
so wonderful play
Argentina are 2-0 up now
uh Angel the Maria is a wonderful player
very talented player and he has scored a
rather easy goal
but very good place
and once again created by Messi once
again Messi has a hand in this or a foot
in this
so yes Argentina now seem to be
holding a very strong upper hand now
let's come back to this question where
did football originate so many cultures
including India have played ball games
including games that involve playing
with the feet uh but the modern game of
football originates in England
association football yeah
but even you could even ask where does
cricket originate so the modern game of
cricket originates in England
and yet Indians used to play with balls
thousands of years ago if you if you
there is this episode in the life of
Shri Krishna Lord Krishna when he was a
kid when he was a young boy
he was playing a certain game ball game
on the banks of the Great yamuna River
yes and the ball goes and falls in the
water
and in the water there is this
this Great Serpent who lives there
kalinag and Krishna goes down into the
water to retrieve the ball
and then the snake he's got a like 10
heads or something he's asleep and his
wives tell Krishna not to disturb the
snake don't disturb him let him sleep
but Krishna wants the ball he goes there
and then there is this fight
you know the story right so what game
was Lord Krishna playing with his with
his friends with his companions it was a
game of bat and ball that they were
playing
so once again you know the true origins
of certain Sports May lie in deep
Antiquity in cultures
that are not the ones that are supposed
to be the ones where it originated so
the modern game of football clearly
originates in England association
football and I think it was in rugby
that they started picking up the ball
with their hands and that became the
sport of rugby as well
or do I watch stand up especially any
Indian comic I
if you want me to name an Indian comic I
would name Russell Peters he is of he's
of Indian origin but he's not Indian
he's Canadian
so I don't really watch stand up I
really enjoy Russell Peters and and uh
in his stand-up act but we've seen it
all
uh any Indian comic of today I think the
Indian Comics are very I'm sure you know
in the old days there used to be a great
stand-up comedy tradition in India it
was called
um
it used to be in Hindi and various
Indian languages and it used to be
poetic but funny
so India has had this tradition for God
knows how many centuries when it comes
to the modern Indian stand-up comics
whether the ones who speak in English or
in Hindi I don't see any real talent in
there because you know it should make me
laugh it should be really funny and
she
the thing about comedy
is you don't make fun of certain of a
specific set of people
you make fun of humanity as a whole
about of you make fun of human nature
you don't make fun of certain
individuals based on political
inclinations or other that's not funny
at all
and these days you have really unfunny
comedians
who and who have this who have this
habit of moralizing and preaching from
the pulpit so that's why I I find Indian
Comedy very operating I am sure there
must be some good comedians which I have
not discovered
but because many of these so-called
prominent comedians are so off-putting
and so unfunny because of that I don't I
don't follow Indian stand-up comedy I I
don't see any real talent among the ones
who are on whom the light on whom the
Limelight is being thrown I'm sure there
is genuine Talent all across India when
it comes to Comedy and I hope really
good talent in the Indian languages
comes to prominence that'll be great but
right now I don't really follow stand-up
comedy it's really boring and really
unfunny and it's annoying the ones who
are prominent but when it comes to
Indian origin guys I think Russell
Peters is ridiculously funny yeah
um
uh yeah yeah you bet
you bet sir
once again the question and once again I
will vary diplomatically say I I will I
no comment no commentitos
uh why are people asking me the same
questions over and over again
come on
do I watch cartoons I I used to watch
cartoons as a kid I used to love
watching cartoons as a kid
uh in the old days you know when I was a
kid you had Disney Mickey Mouse Donald
Duck
um I watched various Japanese cartoons
which you may not remember at all there
was a this series called Robotech it was
Manga
Robotech was wonderful at it I don't
know how many episodes I used to watch
that as a kid as a teenager
um
various French dubbed cartoons Japanese
cartoons dubbed in French I used to
watch you will not know any of those
um DuckTales if anyone remembers from my
childhood and all these days I I don't
know what's what's what's uh what people
watch yeah
I don't know what Shin-chan is I don't
know what Power Rangers are
uh do I watch anime I don't watch enemy
these days
uh so yeah
without a doubt Pete Sampras has has a
better better record if you look at the
overall achievement speed Sampras beats
Andre Agassi hands down one of the
Great's all-time great speech Sampras
how many Grand Slams did Andre I guess
have win
not even I'm sure not even half of that
of Pete Sampras so overall one has to
give it to Pete Chambers yeah
what is the origin of the dogra people
what is the origin of Sindhi people what
is the origin of the himachali people
what is the origin of the Bengali people
what is the origin of the rajput people
of the Tamil people of the kannada
people of the Telugu people the origin
of all the peoples of India is India
itself
that's it I don't get why people want to
know what is the origin of a special
little subset of Indian people if you
look at the genetics of India we all
have the same genetics the skin color
and all those outward characteristics
are unimportant the genetics are very
very very similar alike whether you're
in Afghanistan or whether you are in
Tamil Nadu or in Sri Lanka yeah
so the origin of all the people of India
is India itself India is the Out of
Africa founder Zone the oldest genetic
lineages which are non-african are all
Indian haplogroup F in male lineages
haplogroup M and N in female lineages
the oldest haplogroups non-african hyper
groups are Indian haplogroups a
haplogroup is a genetic lineage
the haplogroups M and N are about 65 000
years old 60 65 000 years old they
originated in India
and similarly for the haplogroup F which
is the uh which more than 90 percent of
non-african males across the world
derive their genetic lineage
from the haplogroup F which is of Indian
origin
so the origin of the dogra people is
within India same as the origin of all
other Indian subcontinent people yes
that is the answer my dear friends
and the reason why people ask this
question is because we are taught that
we India is a multicultural multi-ethnic
multi-racial nation which is absolute
nonsense
um
am I aware of Islam yes obviously
uh MMA fighter one of the upcoming
fighters who defeated what's his name
who defeated that guy I forget the names
from time to time
there's so much data in this head uh
he defeated the the the
Brazilian guy right recently and became
the champion in his weight category so
yes I'm aware of him good fighter
uh used to be loved Jetsons on the
Cartoon Network I I am aware of the
Jetsons it's uh but I never really
watched it yeah
uh Dexter's Lab was fun Dexter's Lab
Courage the Cowardly Dog wonderful
Gravity Falls if anyone has heard of it
there used to be some really good uh you
know
cartoons
hey no need to say sorry it's perfectly
fine
it's perfectly fine ask any question you
like
thank you
Cyrus the Great versus Ashok the great
versus Genghis Khan versus Alexander uh
Cyrus
the thunderous
one of the greatest of the uh
akshamanish Emperors of Persia
uh
he fought the Greeks on occasion if I am
not mistaken if my memory serves me
right one of the great unifiers one of
the great creators of one of the
founders of the of the Persian Empire
so yeah definitely great uh Ashok
clearly the greatest modern Emperor
greater than his grandfather
chandragupta maurya because he created
this enormous unified empire in the
subcontinent unified the entire
subcontinent he finished the job that
his grandfather had set out to do so
Ashok definitely great Alexander was a
warlord a brutal Barbarian
who whose only objective was to conquer
conquer because I have this ego and I
want to show that I am the best yeah so
yeah he is one of the great conquerors
but he cannot hold a candle to chingis
Khan if you want to ask about the
greatest ruler it's a different story if
you want to ask about the greatest
conqueror it's a different story the
greatest conqueror of all time without
question is tringis Khan when chingis
Khan operated on a set of principles he
did not randomly go and Conquer because
he felt like conquering
all his military campaigns were
retaliatory in nature after he became
the the great Khan of the Mongols yes
all his campaigns were Retaliator in
nature it was he had he he was on this
quest to to to to find Justice for his
peoples for his people the Mongol people
um and yet he ended up conquering more
territory in in 20 years than the Roman
emperors put together had come conquered
in 300 years
so you cannot there is nobody that you
can go that you can compare Genghis Khan
to nobody Alexandra is nothing compared
to Chinese Khan
uh
well Cyrus in Ashok were more of
unifiers than conquerors yeah
I'm sure if Ashok had decided to go on a
conquest on a conquering spree he may
have been able to do something like
maybe like the others that you you
mentioned but uh Ashoka was not
interested in conquering foreign lands
he was interested in unifying India the
Indian subcontinent which he succeeded
in doing and then he ruled in peace
and Cyrus also was not he did conquer
territories and all that but he also is
more of a unifier
so that's how it is these are very
different personalities if you want to
compare maybe you could compare Cyrus
and Ashok to a certain extent
and yeah you can compare changes and
Alexander but Alexander is nothing
nothing compared to Chinese Khan was the
greatest of all time legendary
incredible guy
ah yes yes thank you thank you Charles
Oliveira yes Oliveira that's correct
that's who Islam defeated rather easily
rather easily
which sport is the oldest I promise you
the oldest sport in the world is some
form of martial art you know two guys
who may be friends who want to see who's
better
let's see so we will make a set of rules
and then let's go so typically it's
going to be martial arts it's maybe
boxing or or something more you know
that involves a full body kind of
movement you know kicking punching all
that
so I think the oldest sport is most
likely some form of martial arts with
some rules hopefully some rules because
otherwise you're going to end up killing
someone or maiming someone
um
marathons marathons well yeah uh I
remember watching One Marathon once in
my life it was
in 92
Barcelona Olympics
and obviously I was at that time in
India and uh this Marathon was going on
a marathon typically takes three four
hours
and dur darshan the state broadcaster
was was broadcasting the marathon
so I followed the marathon in the
evening
and I don't know who who was winning but
I was kind of following two three people
and at the end it was very interesting
so at the end of the marathon when the
marathon is getting over the last stage
is when you re-enter the stadium in the
last 400 meters you do in there right so
at the point when the
the leaders in the leading group is
about to enter the stadium said okay
end of story it was about 12 o'clock in
the night and they switched off they
could not wait for another two minutes
that's the kind of
practices doordarshan used to have so
yes that is an unforgettable moment in
my life watching that Marathon uh that's
how it used to be that's how bad do
version was I don't miss do darshan many
people are nostalgic about doordarshan I
I don't miss dude darshan whatsoever
pro kabaddi league I am aware of its
existence I'm not really really watched
it
but yeah I'm glad we have a pro kabaddi
league in which players get to play in a
professional manner and earn some good
money that's how you develop a sport it
has to be something that can support you
financially and hopefully make you
reasonably rich as well why not why not
so yeah it gets good to do to have that
did you watch cantata I haven't watched
kantara
I hear it's a good movie but uh I
haven't I haven't watched the Kashmir
files I haven't watched kantara I
watched RR
yeah so kantara I haven't watched yet
maybe I'll try and find some time I
think it's on one of the streaming
services nowadays
um so maybe I'll watch it yeah I hear I
hear very good things about it obviously
um
what other questions do we have
do I think Qatar should play pay
reparations for our workers
why should they do it do I think they
should do it yes they should but they
will not do it
you know there is no justice in the
world my friends
the rich and the powerful will do what
they can
and they will get away with it
the greatest crime in the world is
poverty and weakness and don't blame
others you should know how it happened
you should know how it happens so that
it doesn't happen again but don't blame
others for it
so when I
you know I have been saying this for the
longest time that the reason for India's
backward whatever you want to call it
backwardness poverty all that is the
past 1000 years of foreign occupation
that is the cause
but let's
and obviously the responsibility for for
the plunder the pillage the genocide all
of that lies on the shoulders of the
foreigners the Turks and the Europeans
who did this
yeah
but at the end of the day we were caught
at the wrong time when we were weak and
we were disunited it is at the end of
the day
the fault of the leaders of India at the
time the India should have had a
powerful Emperor who could have unified
the nation if it was that that case then
none of these foreign invasions would
have succeeded
so the greatest
so from today's perspective it is
imperative it is non-negotiable that
India should rise in strength and in
prosperity
the greatest sin is weakness
and being poor yeah and at the end of
the day it doesn't matter how it
happened if you are weak and if you're
poor you will be exploited
okay it is half time it is half time and
Argentina are 2-0 up
great
I if if they win I'll be happy for Messi
I I don't have any as such any soft
corner for the nation of Argentina or
France look at their histories very
interesting histories we will not talk
about that today it's all about Colonial
colonization colonialism
anyhow the thing is I like Messi as an
individual and as a sports person so it
would be good if he can retire on a high
note which it looks like it's going to
be very likely now 2-0 up
what do I think about yuvraj Singh
yuvraj Singh was an extraordinary
talented uh cricketer very very good
batsman
who can forget 2007 the in South Africa
the T20 World Cup that match against uh
uh what's his name what the English
Stuart Broad
bowling and the yuvraj Singh hit six
consecutive sixes yes so yeah incredible
talent I think he could have done better
with his Fitness
for a very long time at least in the
second in the second half of his career
he was kind of overweight kind of
reminds me of Rohit Sharma Rohit Sharma
is you know Roy Sharma is an incredibly
elegant player very talented player Roy
Sharma but
from the way I see him he is the Indian
version of
was great batsman but he was always
overweight
there was this very famous Infamous
incident there was a match in Canada a
one-day match between India and Pakistan
and there was this Indian guy in the
stands in the audience who had a
loudspeaker and he was taunting in Zama
mullah calling him potato
got so Furious he took a bat and tried
to beat the guy up she would have been
arrested for that actually but anyhow
so Rohit Sharma kind of reminds me of
he's like the Indian version of for me
he is overweight issue I mean as a
sports person you should not be
overweight
anyhow so even even yuvraj Singh was
kind of overweight for a very long time
the second half of his career
so I think if he had taken care of his
Fitness properly he would have maybe
achieved more you know yuvraj Singh but
definitely a great great cricketer and
definitely the hero of the 2011 World
Cup yeah and it re it it literally
emerged that he was actually suffering
from a form of cancer at the time and
despite suffering
actively from cancer without knowing it
he was the star performer for India in
the 2011 World Cup
as an all-rounder even as a bowler
so yeah one of the greats one of the
greats in limited old crickets in
limited over Cricket in uh one days one
day matches and 2020 matches not quite
that much in
test matches even though he had a couple
of good innings
I think he scored a wonderful Century
against Australia once in a test match
and all yeah so
yes that is the score right now of
curious monk has updated us France zero
Argentina two
at half time
what went wrong with Tiger Woods well
they said certain personal life issues
crept up and Tiger Woods is most likely
the greatest golfer of all time
incredible Sports person great
achievements
uh his father was American
African-American his mom was from
Thailand
yes
yes what went wrong I mean what went
wrong is that uh
something went wrong in his personal
life his wife's wife divorced him I
think he had some sex addiction or
something like that yeah and uh his wife
divorced him and
and then he had some injuries and all
that now now he's obviously no longer a
young man
I'm not sure if he's still active as a
golfer
but yeah his record is obviously one of
the greatest of all time for sure
um
what do I think of Pakistan's recent
atomic bomb threat to India's
I think it's cute I think it's a cute
cute thing to say
atomy bomb
uh let's talk about something we have je
in one month no look if you if you hope
to prepare for an exam like the GE in
once in one month's time it is it is
likely to fail
to prepare for something at the GE you
need to have a one year time frame and
prepare systematically over a period of
one year every day spend like three
hours a day that is very much feasible
compared to spending 12 hours a day for
a month that will burn your brain out
so uh and the thing is don't put too
much pressure on yourselves I know it's
a high stakes exam you want to get into
the iits and all that good God what am I
seeing on the screen no no no no no no
ah I cannot unsee that
why
why anyhow we will not talk about that
uh who is my favorite golidanda player
well
um I I think I played it a few times as
a kid but uh yeah I'm not sure if
there's any professional League or so so
I don't know I don't know
gymnastics tonight's ice skating we have
a good gymnast that girl right what's
her name Deepa Deepa karmakar or
something
uh she came fourth in the Olympics once
um gymnastics is is a good good sport
yeah you need to be light in body in
very very very flexible so it's not for
everybody certainly not for somebody
like me I'm too large I was always too
large for gymnastics but yeah if you are
short if you are slim and if you're
flexible but strong then gymnastics is
great ice skating
[Music]
um
there is written the yeah ice skating is
also it's it's also a niche sport kind
of
it's it's all it's got it's got its own
place in the pantheon of various Sports
yeah
is Shri Krishna the greatest human being
of all time maybe maybe one of the top
human beings of all time ever yes for
sure
we consider him to be a God today he is
a historical he was a historical figure
he was a flesh and blood human being
and
he lived thousands of years ago and we
still worship him today so imagine the
impact here yeah he had
clearly one of the all-time great human
beings of all time imagine remembering
something somebody for thousands of
years
and Lord Ram came thousands of years
before Lord Krishna so yeah these are
two of the greats maybe the top two of
all time perhaps yeah
do I like the Beatles
um The Beatles were never
obviously they're a great band I I have
never spent too much time listening to
The Beatles they had some nice songs
but uh
not exactly my taste I don't dislike the
beetles
uh
you know which bands were my favorite or
kind of still are
Pink Floyd for some time I was really
obsessed with Pink Floyd for some time
nowadays I don't listen to Pink Floyd
it's it's too
I mean it's brilliant for sure
but it's kind of dark and gloomy
much much of their music Pink Floyd is
is about mental illness and and dark
themes and depressing themes and all
that so despite uh the music being
brilliant I I don't spend a lot of time
or any time at all listening to it some
of it is very interesting like some of
it has sci-fi connotations philosophical
connotations there is a song by Pink
Floyd which essentially is is a hymn to
the Sun son the sun god essentially it's
called echoes
that's a great song that's something I
don't mind listening again listen to
again the Pink Floyd have where one of
the greats but I would say if you were
to ask me my favorite band of all time I
would say Led Zeppelin a band from the
1670s 80s not not the 80s 60s 70s one of
the great bands of all time ever yeah
Led Zeppelin Beatles not so much
um not so much I did not find it I don't
know
intellectual enough no it's not only
about Led Zeppelin is not intellectual
but yeah it's great
so I don't dislike the Beatles but it's
not been one of my favorite bands for
sure
all right all right
um
what is One Direction I think it's a boy
band of some kind yes One Direction yeah
I I
am
not quite into boy bands
uh linking Park you know the thing about
American rock bands is
there are two kinds of rock bands when
it comes to rock music one is British
broadbands rock bands and a second is
American Rockets American rock bands
sound like noise to me I I I have
nothing against the people of America
but most American rock bands sound like
noise
very loud and very noisy and no nuance
I mean so linking Park I I there is this
one song that everybody plays that I'm
aware of that that's one there's this
band called Green Day
they had one or two uh good songs Eagles
were were reasonably good
band I had their album Hell Freezes Over
in the old days when you had those
cassette tapes I had that now I have
MP3s somewhere I ripped it out of the
tape yeah so Eagles were good Hotel
California everyone knows and various
other songs Eagles were great
um Led Zeppelin like I said yes
Beethoven good good better one obviously
that's classical music I have a good
band Dancing Queen that's not obviously
my kind of song
uh Dancing Queen and voulez-vous and all
that yeah
uh Rolling Stones Rolling Stones
somebody asked me about Rolling Stone I
saw it somewhere yeah Rolling Stones
they had some good songs
what
I forget the name of the song but yeah
they had some good songs but Rolling
Stones too once again were not one of my
favorite bands Coldplay is okay
Oasis was good a few of their songs were
good Oasis
Guns and Roses were good for a while and
then they they broke up but Guns and
Roses yes it's one of the few American
bands that actually liked rock bands
Axle Rose
incredible very unique voice yeah
and uh what's the guy's name the guitar
player
I forget his name great guitar player
the guy with the hat the guy with the
curly hair
yeah
um Eminem he has
um
Red Hot Chili Peppers yeah some some
good songs there yeah
Metallica Metallica Goods a good good
band good band
uh which European languages do I speak I
speak French I understand bits and
pieces of other languages I can speak a
few words here in their few phrases
if you speak French you understand many
of the romance languages the Latin
languages Italian Spanish Portuguese yes
uh Latin two so these are all very
closely connected languages so if you
know French you will understand a bit of
Italian I mean if you especially written
Italian and Spanish and all that
so mainly it's it's French
that I actually at one time French was
maybe my primary language at one point
in time a very long time ago and uh
because I speak English I obviously
understand a bit of German
English is by the way a Germanic
language yeah
um
that's right
please watch Death Note the new one not
the original one I think the original
one is better Kira Kira Kira
this is a
Shinigami the the creature right the the
spirit yeah I think I I think I've seen
an episode or two I think it was great
it was good
I don't really watch Family Guy I is it
funny I watch The Simpsons a lot as a
kid Simpsons was good
Justin Bieber I think Justin Bieber is
actually a talented singer but uh people
are kind of
focusing more on his personal life and
his Persona uh I think he's a talented
singer he's a kid that was a very
talented singer the first song what was
it maybe
uh yeah about 10-15 years ago he broke
out as a big star because of that one
song
thoughts of Billy Joel I think you won a
Grammy at some point everybody missed
out on granny I'm not sure he had some
good songs
We Didn't Start the Fire and the river
of something he had some some good songs
good good more of a gospel singer or
something if I'm not mistaken
yeah
boy like video games and I don't really
play games I I had a p you know I had
one of the old PlayStations PS2 I think
and there was this this game I used to
play Dynasty Warriors was one and then
there was this car game you know car
racing car crashing more of I used to
play that
uh so yeah
so I I as a kid I never had access to
video games you know I I was in 80s and
90s kid so in those days we do not have
video games at least I do not have
access to any so I I suppose if I had
access to those I would have been I
would have been enjoying that
but yeah so I had a PS2 for the longest
time I used more as a DVD player but I
played a few of those games and these
days I don't really play any games yeah
so yeah that but I'm sure it's it's
funny it's fun to play
favorite Led Zeppelin song right I think
Led Zeppelin 4 is the favorite album
lots of good songs
The Rain Song is good very very
interesting chords they've used very
interesting very pretty Blues chords
The Rain Song then there's the Immigrant
Song with the Viking Viking Invasion
song essentially uh Stairway to Heaven
I think most of the 80 of the music is
wonderful the and you know Led Zeppelin
is considered to be the the original the
the band that is that that created
heavy metal music that's what that's the
perception that people have of Led
Zeppelin and yet about 40 of their songs
are acoustic acoustic guitar
they had very economic influences uh Led
Zeppelin were influenced by by Indian
music by Middle Eastern music my Celtic
music a lot of folk influences in Led
Zeppelin that's why it's such an
interesting man
very talented and very unique musicians
all four of them the lead singer Robert
Plant is
half of money his mother was like he
said a gypsy so he has Indian origin his
wife was anglo-indian his kids are all
you know they look like half Indian kind
of you know so yeah very very impressive
band
um
issue in my mic hello can you hear me
all right
my views on Andrew Huber man's podcasts
I haven't seen any of his podcasts
podcasts take a lot of time to watch but
I I hear is very popular and I'm sure
he's got a very interesting information
to share I saw some tips of him of his
on on Joe Rogan interesting guy
definitely very interesting guy
definitely very knowledgeable very well
read very
accomplished researcher so yeah
let's see what other questions do we
have
how to increase weight
eat more than we do
if you are if you are at a certain way
you only have to eat more the more
calories you put in
the more weight you will gain obviously
you should not eat junk food with the
right kind of food hopefully something
that that is clean something that is not
processed and get some adequate protein
and
you're sorry for me
either clean carbohydrates like lots of
vegetables or rice or wheat
or fat like ghee or or if you eat meat
whatever you know that sort of thing and
if you want to increase weight go and
lift some weights in the gym go lift
weights you're going to put a muscle if
you do
um so you're a boy you're a male right
so if you eat more if you eat clean and
you eat more protein and use let's say
you spend six months in the gym on a
proper weightlifting program you're
gonna gain weight you're gonna easily
gain weight yeah that's how you do it I
mean everybody has a different kind of
metabolism all some people find it
easier to gain weight some people find
it harder to gain weight some people are
called hard gainers and all but you need
to find out what works best for the body
and I'm sure if you find the right
program in the right dietary plan for
yourself you will
gain weight for sure
um
went and conquered much of Central Asia
but so definitely one of the great
conquerors they conquered a lot in one
lifetime yeah conquered Tibet as well
but Twinkies conquered more I don't
think this anybody in human history in
in recorded or known human history who
has conquered more inventory than the
great Genghis Khan yeah
so there is no con it's a no contest
essentially
my views on avatar the way of water I
haven't watched it yet it just came out
I mean a few days ago three four days
ago I haven't watched it I think I if I
find the time I will go and watch it I
watched Avatar one I think I watched it
twice in the movie theater twice
it was it was that good not the story
not the story but but the the
visualization the visualization the
first 3D movie that I saw and uh yeah
the way it was filmed in the scenery Etc
the planet is the moon is is depicted
Pandora it's so pretty that you know
this you don't care if the story is not
good enough the story was also kind of
okay
it's a white savior story at the end of
the day but yeah it was really uh a
pleasure to watch a visual pleasure and
the the music was great James Horner I
think he passed away
so and I I hear good things about Avatar
who I think it's usually even a better
spectacle it's even a bigger treat than
the previous one so I think hopefully
and I and if you look at the reviews I
think the reviews are all mainly
positive
so I think it will be worth watching so
maybe if I find the time I'll go and
watch it most likely I will
can one increase one's height after the
age of 90 most likely not
I think uh you you grow until the age of
18 19 maybe 20
but your main growth sport is after
after the answer of puberty so that's
around 13 14 until 17 18 19. after that
I think I think as far as I know
obviously I'm not a
a biologist or anything but as far as I
understand after 19 it's kind of
difficult to increase height a lot in
some rare cases you may be able to do
that but not much but that's okay listen
your height doesn't matter
what you do in your life that's what
matters there are many great people who
are short and there are many great
people who are tall but usually it's
shorter people who did more I guess yeah
so it doesn't matter but uh yeah that's
how it is
height matters I don't know I mean
there's no harm in being tall I would
never I I
it's never
it's not a disadvantage to be tall but
it's not a disadvantage to be short
either you know we don't live in a world
where you have to be a warrior to
succeed in life
your physical abilities are not not that
important in today's world right so
that's okay so height doesn't really
matter of course if you are tall it
gives you a psychological advantage I
suppose yeah people feel great if you're
if they're taller and stronger than
others I suppose
but I I it's okay it's not a big deal
he was not a tall man
and I believe even Julius Caesar was not
a tall man
Alexander is supposed to have been a
shorty
shorty I I need no disrespect to anyone
who's short I'm just saying yeah
so it's okay height doesn't matter
okay now the other iteration is the size
Matters yes if your wide broad muscular
it may matter it may make you feel good
and so on and I will stop at that
uh I'm six four then you go see who says
Indians can be tall of course Indians
can be tall you know there are lots of
people lots of kids these days who are
all six feet tall six feet plus tall
Indians are overall getting taller
especially the the younger kids
so yeah it's good Maradona five five
there you go and so on
perfectly fine
what's the ideal height your whatever
height you get in life is your ideal
height doesn't matter there's no such
thing as an ideal height uh there you
have it suction five five okay
um
all right
another tall guy
good
so it's it's fine 5 10 5 10 average I
don't know what's the average height for
males in India today is it five ten uh
maybe less not sure I'm not sure what it
is
it doesn't matter either way
okay average Indian male height is five
seven right now you know in a decade
will be five eight five nine I suppose
yeah
is uh six one
okay some people are being funny that's
all right
okay somebody is 198 centimeters 198
centimeters
Hall is 5 10.
Amir Khan is fine
all right all right all right that's
great okay okay I'm not taking any more
height uh questions
Radiohead Radiohead was was is is a good
band
uh what's that song that the greatest
song that they had it's
why do I forget the names of songs and
all that
um creep creep maybe you had creep one
of the great songs yeah
correct
when you had is an interesting band Yes
Mac Pro is 510 why am I doing this again
even though I said it's not important
height versus looks I think um
it it helps to be good looking of course
but you know what there are lots of good
looking people who achieve nothing in
life
and there are lots of people who are not
considered to be from the classical
perspective to be apparently good
looking more averaging looking whatever
who do great in life
a person who is successful people don't
care what he or she looks like
trust me
if you are successful then no one cares
what you look like but many of the most
successful people in the world think of
the people who you consider to be very
successful
and ask yourself is this is that person
really good looking think of all the
sports people who are successful was
Diego Maradona a good looking man I
would say he was an average looking man
he was not especially good looking what
about
what about what do you think of him he
is considerably one of the greatest
cricketers of all time yes
and so on and so forth so what about
Elon Musk is he a handsome man from a
classical Definition of handsome yeah
and and so on you know so it doesn't
really matter
what matters is what you do with your
life that's what really matters
um
sarcasm or wit how to master them I have
no idea if you I mean I suppose some
people are just born with certain
qualities with what you call it or
sarcasm and maybe some people perfect
that over their lifetime
most likely these things are skills and
as with any skill the more you practice
it the better you get
at it so
so I think sarcasm is is more of a
negative thing compared to whip you know
so how to master something practice
practice you try to figure out how it is
done
um
let's see
Elon Musk is an alien yeah maybe this is
possible it's possible my thoughts about
yadav he is a wonderful player very very
interesting player very interesting
technique 360 Degrees player
right now he's playing uh better than
how the pandya for instance you know
so yeah I think he's a wonderful player
it's good to have someone like him in
the cricket team
why was Ben Franklin's basement filled
with skeletons
I think that's a question for Ben
Franklin to answer or for historians and
investigative sponsor but yes it appears
that um
the guy had a cupboard full of skeletons
apparently yeah
do you think coup can replace Twitter
why don't you use cool I have I I had I
have a cool account I had created an
account I don't know when a year two
years ago it was extremely unfriendly it
was really frustrating to use
uh I don't know how it is now when I
tried it it was like a cheap listen I'm
not trying to disparage it it was like
an inferior knockoff of Twitter it was
the thing new Innovative in it it was
really
hard to use it was buggy it was clunky
um I tried using it I have an account
I'm sure I'm sure you can Google it but
yeah so like the past year or two years
I have not even looked at it I'm I'm
sure I could revisit it
um
so I don't know whether who can replace
Twitter if you want to replace Twitter
you have to do better than Twitter
if you do the same thing why should
somebody move off Twitter and go to
Chrome you have to offer something that
that Twitter can't offer you know
something some Advantage something
better
and when a platform has an enormous user
base like Twitter already has it's
really hard to convince people to move
off it and go to one of the platform
unless this new platform offers
something that simply can't offer so
cool I think it's just like a replica in
some ways of Twitter and I believe some
Indians are on cool and I heard that it
was popular for some time in Brazil also
yeah
so if it is doing well good for it
we obviously in India would like to have
we would need to have our own social
media platforms that's a good thing so
whoever has created cool I'm I'm sure
it's a it's a good thing I would like to
encourage them but my suggestion would
be to to make it user-friendly it should
be a pleasure to use it should not be
like an annoying thing
and it should have something Innovative
something that other platforms don't
offer yeah
so if you can do that it's great so do I
think Twitter can cook and replace
Twitter I think it'll be hard for it to
to do that but if it happens I'll be
really happy yeah why don't I scoop like
I said because it was really unfriendly
or unfriendly it was buggy clunky not a
pleasure to use so I stopped using it
I'm on Twitter
and if cool becomes good again in the
future I'll be happy to use it yeah
the thing is you can't it's you can't
spend your time all day on social media
platforms you can have one maybe or two
but having a presence on like lots of
different social media platforms it's
it's too much of a brain on your time
so ideally someone like me I would like
to have one or two places I have YouTube
I have Twitter and that's I have an
Instagram that is not really active
right now but it's there and that's
about it I also have Facebook this thing
is going live on Facebook right now as
well
um also on Twitch I have a twitch I
think this is streaming live on Twitch
as well right now but yeah
but my main uh places are obviously
YouTube and Twitter and to some to a
small extent Instagram
but it would be good to have uh Indian
social media platforms
I've never used Java personally have you
seen
uh so she was fine she was fun to lose
she was something that replaced four
crime in the in the science in the
science community in the physics
community so when I was a student
in University I used C for programming
writing programs in nuclear physics and
all that you know so yeah C was fun at
the time I'm sure python is much more
user friendly and much more of a
pleasure to use these days
uh so yeah so since I don't have any
experience in Java so I can't really say
but C was was fun to use when I
used it
all right
[Music]
um
well I haven't seen it so what can I say
if I see it I shall talk of it
if I find it interesting
okay sir I've replied to you go study
for example I don't know what's
happening these days on Twitter everyone
wants me to reply and if you reply I
will do this
uh okay whatever anyway go for it study
yes study
Whiplash I I think I've seen the movie
and it was a movie about uh music
jazz music or some kind of music
it was a reasonably fun movie to watch I
think it was a good movie it was an
interesting movie a different concept
I don't remember much of it today but
yes it was a movie that I was able to
see the whole of it what's the whole of
it without getting too bored yeah
whiplash
the the main character of the
protagonist was a drummer that's correct
a drummer
yes I have watched whiplash
yes drum correct drum
yes
all right
my views on Oppenheimer the movie the
series The guy I suppose the guy well he
was essentially the guy who was in
charge of the Manhattan Project the
American nuclear bomb program
in the 1940s that's the program that
gave the Americans goes to Atomic
devices that they tested on the Japanese
people I'm a Japanese civilian
population and uh yeah Oppenheimer
obviously
he was not very happy with how his
creation was used he was a nuclear
physicist
and uh
and then later on in his life he was
accused of being a communist sympathizer
or something and his career was kind of
destroyed lots of ugly politics in all
that yeah and obviously in India he's
famous for for uh
for uh his views
philosophical views you know when the
first atomic bomb test was done the
Trinity test
when he saw the the device explode he
was reminded of this of of a verse from
the bhagavad-gita or something like that
yeah so that's why Indians are very fond
of him because he had these this
inclination towards Indian philosophy
and Hinduism and all that yeah so that's
that's what I know of him
um
so what's going on it's two zero two
zero and Angel de Maria has been
substituted he has done his job he's got
the second goal good job sir
and if it is enough for his team then
he'll be the happiest guy in the world
good so he has been substituted and the
match goes on 2-0 64 minutes in
let us see France is up against it the
French guys are up against it they have
their backs to the wall and Argentina is
attacking Argentina is doing well Messi
has the ball
and the game is being played in the
French half right now
good God Messi
yes interesting period of play
dangerous
it's all defense for the French right
now oh
handball no
all right so it's so that's what's going
on that's what's going on in the match
looks like the argentines will win
should I should I speak closer to the
mic is this better no I don't think so
okay
my opinion on the Moroccan Behavior
after their loss to France I think the
Moroccan players were reasonably well
behaved and that I will leave it at that
the Moroccan players were reasonably
well behaved
I mean
yeah it is what it is
it is what it is
I think we should watch MMA or boxing
matches like this well the um the UFC
telecasts are typically in the morning
for in in India Indian time it's morning
it's typically in the U.S in the in the
evening in the US American time
America the U.S has like three or four
different time zones five if I'm not
mistake they have a Hawaiian Time as
well
if it's in Las Vegas
then it's and in the evening over there
then it's early morning for India
so yeah if you want I I do watch it on
occasion
I usually miss that I you watch watch a
replay or whatever
but yes maybe we could do it in the
future if you all are are open to
watching a live stream in the morning
yeah maybe
um
yeah
any other question have you seen the
movie Passengers
I have not seen the movie Passengers
I have not seen it
what do I think about MMA becoming an
Olympic sport you make MMA an Olympic
sport it's gonna get corrupted
for instance if you see how what's
happened to football or sorry
to boxing in the Olympics if you watch
the various
matches Olympic boxing matches you will
see a lot of cheating on the part of the
judges
there I don't remember I think it was in
2012. the Olympic Games 2012 London
Olympics
there was this Japanese boxer
what was his name I think his name was
Satoshi Shimizu Satoshi Shimizu he
knocked out he knocked out his opponent
10 or 12 times and he was awarded a loss
imagine knocking out your opponent 10 or
12 times and then the judges say you've
lost
that's what happened there is a lot of
cheating and corruption in the Olympics
at least in boxing I've seen that I've
seen that person with my own eyes you
can look it up go to YouTube and search
for the Satoshi Shimizu 2012 Olympics
it's ridiculous
and that's not the only one that's the
first thing that came to my mind
I think if you bring MMA into Olympics
it's gonna ruin MMA
let MMA be out of out of the Olympics
and be run by a private organization
like zuffa and uh
it's it's I think they're doing a good
job I think Dana White has been a good
job of running the show yeah I'm sure
the the players will be paid more that's
one criticism that one sees that the MMA
players are not play are not paid
anything like what professional boxes
would be paid
for instance a professional boxer a top
class professional boxer can easily make
50 million 100 million dollars for one
fight
I mean really Top Class you know like
like a world champion kind of guy
uh and even uh a reasonably good
professional boxer can can make a good
income out of boxing but when you see
the fight purse for the MMA fighters
it's much lower than any than any boxer
so that's one criticism that has been um
leveled at MMA at the UFC then that
seems to be a kind of valid and
legitimate criticism but apart from that
I think it's being run well
professionally
reasonably professionally
of course there was this one fight
recently Paddy the Baddie who won
against somebody and clearly here not
performed so well so sometimes you have
these problems that's something you have
in every sport but I would not like to
see MMA come into the Olympics I think
they will ruin it ruin it
um
the only 90 idea says you would not be
able to focus anywhere maybe I may not
be able to focus because when you're
watching a fight your attention is going
to be more on that in football I can
talk while keeping half an eye on what's
happening there when it comes to a
really good fight it's impossible to not
pay attention there and so then I will
not be able to focus here or there so
yeah maybe MMA is not a good idea
unless I just do commentary but I don't
know how to do commentary
uh have I watched arrival 2016. I did
watch arrival I like science fiction I'm
a huge fan of Science Fiction as a kid I
used to read only science fiction
initially then I moved to other genres
as well
so yes I I'm a huge fan of Science
Fiction I love science fiction moves as
well I watched arrival 2016. I found it
boring and pretentious it's an art movie
trying pretending to be a science
fiction movie
so um if you were to ask me which is the
most interesting science fiction movie
I've seen in the past 10 years I would
definitely say Interstellar really good
movie some of it was kind of the science
see
the the last part in which the guy goes
into inside the black hole and then
encounters God knows what that is
speculation that's not really hard
science but apart from that it was
really good the way they showed the
black hole and all that that was
wonderful so and and the story was great
so intercella was wonderful arrival was
pretentious and boring from my
perspective and lots of people will
disagree with me which is fine
which is fine but it was not a science
fiction movie it was an art movie it was
a fantasy movie trying to pretend to be
a science fiction movie and and I I
think it's got good reviews and ratings
but from my perspective it was not my
cup of tea
I I've watched it only once I I I I
think I've watched interest at least
twice on a big screen twice I think so
yeah
what is Big Boss
some reality TV thing I have never ever
watched a single episode of big boss so
I don't know
no no idea sorry
you see a Stephen King book somewhere my
background somewhere
could be perhaps
I do have some Stephen King books uh
what are my favorite books by Stephen
King
I haven't read a lot of Stephen King I
read this book I don't know how many
years ago I think I read it in 2002 when
I was in the U.S
it was called bag of bones it was a
ghost story kind of Horror Story a good
story long long book link the book it
takes like 60 70 Pages for the real
story to actually start you know there's
a lot of character building and all that
uh atmosphere building in in setting
milieu building and all that but good
book overall
so I read bag of bones it's a it's a
Ghost Story horror story not very scary
um that's one that comes to mind I I'm
sure I've read a couple more but I don't
remember which I'm sure I have some
books here and there but yeah so that's
the one that comes to mind immediately
Stephen King uh what are my favorite
fiction books in general
uh I don't know I've read so many books
they they all kind of mix up in my mind
um
fiction books
The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy is
a fun book to read it's science fiction
but it's funny it's it's comedy science
fiction and good story that's a good one
by Douglas Adams the late Douglas Adams
that's good
um
I would say
um the Lord of the Rings
I have read a lot of the Rings many
times it's a huge thick book and the
more you read the more you discover
about the story The the and the writer
so yeah there are elements of white
Supreme supremacism in it there are
elements of racism in it for sure the
deeper you go into it the more you
discover you know what it's like but
overall it's a great story
it's all it's a very good story so yeah
the Lord of the Rings uh The
Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy I don't
know how many books I must have read
I've learned I've read a lot of books by
Arthur C Clarke some were terrible like
the like the Rama series with Rama The
Garden of Rama and all that really
really tedious books to read
I don't know how I finished those books
but some books by Arthur City Clark are
wonderful
uh there's a short story called
what's it called
I forget the name
um
the hammer of God in which there is this
they discover a comet
which they call Kali because that comet
is on a trajectory to intercept the
Earth so that's an interesting story the
songs of distant Earth lots of good good
books by by Arthur C Clarke and I I
don't know so my favorite genre for the
longest time was science fiction
nowadays I read all kinds of stuff yeah
but nowadays I read more non-fiction
Than Fiction
Marvel or DC
um Marvel is all garbage these days the
last Marvel movie I saw was
what was it Multiverse of misery
I don't know I don't even know what's
the difference between DC and Marvel
anymore it's all become a blur
the Batman move the Batman movies are
terrible these days very dark depressing
and gloomy and you may find it
surprising that I am criticizing Batman
because lots of people seem to love
Batman
if you watch the you know as a kid I
watched the original Batman series the
original Batman series was
was from the 1960s or something
yeah and uh
it was really funny it was light-hearted
it was funny it was positive and it was
not gloomy at all it was not dark
depressing full of misery so that's how
I had seen Batman and then if you look
at all these new movies ugh
depressing dark gloomy horrible
so yeah
a lady thought with fake muscles I mean
turning Natalie Portman into Thor
it's so disrespectful to the original
mythology
there's this new movie I saw
in which you had Thor and Zeus at the
same time
Thor is played by that guy and Zeus was
the guy who played Gladiator Zeus was
fat and and and and
irresponsible the king of the Gods the
truth
is that Thor and Zeus are the same God
Thor is the Nordic or Viking version of
the Greek Zeus
which is the same as the Roman Jupiter
and the origin of all these divinities
is the Indian Indra
it's the same God you can't say you
can't
pit Thor versus Zeus you can put the
same God against the same God it's
ridiculous how they have disrespected
and distorted the original mythology yes
and then now they have a lady version of
each so-called superhero horrific
horrific I I I I've stopped watching all
this nonsense really it's terrible
my views on Pablo Escobar here one of
the great drug smugglers but not the
greatest drug Smuggler of all time the
greatest drug Smuggler that ever emerged
out of Colombia most likely Senor Pablo
Escobar he met uh when he died he was
killed by the by the Americans the FBI
if I'm not mistaken yes
so the greatest Colombian drugs Smuggler
but do you know who's the greatest drug
Smuggler of all time
it is the queen of the British
Queen Victoria
she was the greatest drug Smuggler of
all time
Pablo Escobar was not even one percent
of what she was
so yeah
that's what it was yeah
Bollywood versus tollywood so Bollywood
is No-No I don't watch Bollywood anymore
at all garbage absolute utter garbage
uh tollywood what is Hollywood there are
lots of woods these days
uh Collywood tollywood I don't know what
else is there I think it's one of the
South Indian things yeah
South Indian movie Industries yeah so I
I would so I I enjoyed what's the name
of the the bahubali movie part I saw the
part two I haven't seen part one I saw
part two it was great I liked it
uh do we have one more penalty
do we have one more penalty
so I definitely am not a big fan of
Bollywood anymore they have been fooling
us for decades
for decades they've been fooling us
and nowadays I'm glad to see that people
are realizing that and the quality is
just abysmal in Bollywood thesis who
wants to see a 70 year old hero
pretending to be a college student
yeah hero
so
so yeah I'm happy to watch anything
apart from Bollywood I don't care if
it's a Telugu movie or a Tamil movie or
a kannada movie or a Bengali movie or a
thulu movie or or whatever other
language yeah
I think the South has has taken over and
I'm really really happy to see that so
it looks like the French have a penalty
so the French may be able to come back
and this will make the match really
interesting
mbappe is about to take a penalty come
on boy
yes sir keep your cool it should be 2-1
I would like to say that
will he be able to do it let's see
and he is he does it yes mbappe
scores a penalty
I miss you my cone make sure my clone is
watching the match he's there in person
in Qatar I mean he's like punching the
air and DJ Edition is happy now
is the coach of France he was the
captain in 1998. the World Cup winning
captain
and mbappe has scored it is 2-1 which
makes the last
15-20 minutes very interesting
it's gonna be fun now
Argentina fall back up on defense or
will the attack
that's the question that's the question
good fun
yeah this makes this World Cup final
more interesting
the south is rocking these days I'm
really happy to see that everything was
monopolized by Bollywood by the Urdu
film industry come on enough of that
enough of that
so I'm glad to see lots of great movies
coming out of the south of India really
good to see that
what was pre-christian Europe like what
religion did they follow
they followed the old Indo-European
religion which was various different
local offshoots of Vedic Hinduism that's
what it was
multiple gods of you know polytheism a
Pantheon of gods and also the worship of
nature the worship of ancestors all
those things
uh so that's what it was and obviously
uh
they did not follow Vedic Hinduism
various local offshoots of that and
obviously they they they had various
local practices and tutu
in Baptist scored a second goal it's 2-2
the French came back from two zero down
it's 2-2 now would you believe it
I'm sure my cone is incredibly happy
what an incredible comeback how did this
happen
so Argentina have messed up they once
again let go of a 2-0 lead
uh in their in their match against the
Dutch they were 2-0 up and the Dutch
were able to come back to 2-2
and now they have done the same thing
against France
2-2
good God
what is wrong about with Argentina
Breaking Bad one of the greatest series
I've seen in my life
I've watched it the whole thing
wonderful incredible
great characters great characters great
story
nothing boring or annoying about it yes
so yes it's one of the great series I've
seen
Breaking Bad
so
um
oh no messy it looks it now Messi's
hands are no longer on the World Cup
mbappe has scored twice in like three
minutes four minutes whatever it is
as friends is back France is back good
for them
uh I have seen I have watched Game of
Thrones it was really interesting the
first I don't know how many seasons was
it in total seven or eight
the last two seasons weren't great the
last season was terrible the ruined the
whole story in the last season but
before that it was good it's not for
everybody
yeah
but yeah I really enjoyed the Game of
Thrones the original few seasons
um
Argentina lost the 1990 final yes we
know 2014 they lost to the Germans
yes and this time there are two two they
came back I mean they were winning but
they're now 2-2 so let's see if that
record continues or will they be able to
come out again now they have to attack
if they had thought of Defending then
that that is now out of the question
they have to attack
so let's see what happens
they are attacking again the argentines
and uh let's see how that goes but one
thing is for sure this has become a
really interesting match now
bang bang going on
Inception I think I saw it but I don't
remember much of it I think I have to
see it properly to understand it's a
very
I think complex story
better call Seoul I haven't watched it
so don't know don't know about uh Fight
Club great movie fantastic movie Fight
Club
uh Brad Pitt and Edward Norton great
story great movie one of the iconic
movies from the 1990s
uh peaky blinders I haven't watched it
yet so I can't say
all right
um
unknown says can one crack an EET in
four months uh it depends
if your Basics are good if you have then
I'm sure four months is enough to really
go all out
and uh practice the strategies and
tactics you know just solving lots of
old exam papers or or whatever strategy
you want to use so if your Basics are
good if your fundamentals are good then
it's it's possible but if you have to
learn the fundamentals and then crack an
80 I think that's difficult
so as long as your fundamentals are good
your Concepts conceptually you are good
in math and science in physics and
whatever else then I think it should be
not very difficult
to do it in four months
uh right
um
uh what happens if the match is tied if
the match is tied at 2-2 let's say it
will go into extra time so two halves or
15 minutes each
and if it is still tied after that it
will go to a penalty shootout and then
it will be decided one way or the other
that's how it goes
um
please watch the peripherals peripherals
I haven't heard of it what it sounds
like science fiction I don't know okay
we'll see
um
what else Messi gave away the second
goal ah bad bad very naughty boy
disappointing sir disappointing
um
I'm I'm not aware of this in this person
have I watched that Poet Society no I
have not
are there any other Hindu god parallels
with different cultures other than Indra
this loves have this uh
this Trinity this composite God called
triglav three glove which is essentially
the Brahma Vishnu Shiva
and they have the same names Brahma
Vishnu sivoy or something like that you
know the Slavic peoples so yeah there
are lots of parallels that you see
in various cultures
um
Matrix is a is it's a great movie
wonderful movie
Matrix is a wonderful movie I think I
saw it twice or Thrice in a theater yeah
um
Big Bang Theory I think I've seen a few
episodes the first season the second
season was good
then I hear that it becomes uh they they
kind of ruined it that's what I hear I
don't I'm not seeing it yeah I'm not
seeing the later Seasons I think I've
seen some of the episodes in the season
one and
and I think people have this belief that
most theoretical physicists are like
Sheldon Cooper which is not the case
uh
have I read Dune yes I have read it I've
got this somewhere behind me or
somewhere else I have it somewhere I
have reduned the first book good book
it's it's not an easy read but it's a
good book
it's one of the great great books
James Bond or Mission Impossible I think
I would go with James Bond as a kid I
watched a lot of James Bond you know
Sean Connery Roger Moore and even Pierce
Brosnan was good
even Daniel Daniel Craig was good so
uh yeah so so from a personal
perspective I would say James Bond I
enjoyed that more and now I don't know
who's gonna be the next James Bond and
whether they're gonna ruin the character
or not which is very likely very
possible yeah
um
so yeah I would I would definitely say
James Bond over
over that other thing stranger things I
haven't watched it I hear it's good I
don't know
uh BR Chopra Mahabharata great great
even though the the costumes are like
stage costumes and the special effects
are very rudimentary and yet it's the
greatest
version of the Mahabharata ever filmed
thus far I'm sure there are more newer
versions of Mahabharata that have come
on on TV I've not watched any of those
but the one that that always resonates
with me is the BR Chopra version of
Mahabharata
yeah uh
Ein Rand novels I have read
Atlas Shrugged and I have read The
Fountainhead
that's like more than 20 years ago and
at one point in time I was like very
impressed with that these days I I have
a better more holistic perspective of
the world the iron brand philosophy is
all about selfishness the virtue of
being selfish but if every person is
selfish and they develop themselves to
the fullest extent then it's great for
the world I think it's a myopic View
yeah at that time when I was was it was
a was a student
I was really
impressed with iron Rand and her her
books these two books and there was this
professor of Economics that I interacted
with
so he was like what do you think he
asked me once what do you think of Enron
I was like I'm so it's so great and all
he was like um not quite the case and I
thought he's stupid you know when you're
young you think you know everything and
everybody else is stupid so I was like
what is wrong with this guy such a
wonderful philosophy ideology or
whatever now I I am with him today so if
I meet him today I would say yes you're
right
so yeah
but it's something that's definitely
worth a read
definitely was definitely worth a read
the characters are unlikable
Howard Rorke is an unlikable character
actually it's these are just you know
mediums for expounding a certain
philosophy or ideology but definitely
worth a read it's something that
is worth reading I would say and you may
learn something from that or get a
certain perspective on life
but yeah it's a today I'm not the
biggest fan of that
foreign
do I think there are extraterrestrials
on Mount kailash well I don't know
I I don't know How Will I Know I haven't
been there I've seen some videos on in
which there appears to be some
uh activity there that cannot quite be
explained so possible but I don't know
do I think I'm not sure so I
so I can't answer yes or no I don't know
that's the only answer that I can give
how to deal with mentally colonized
people okay there are eight extra
minutes of injury time okay we'll go
back to that how do you deal with
mentally colonized people
you don't deal with them
you don't try to change their opinion
you don't try to argue with them
once you realize somebody is mentally
colonized you will say good luck to them
you go away with your life
if you
do change your mind at some point in
time it's up to you it's not your
responsibility to change everyone's mind
one thing I've learned in life is don't
argue with people if somebody has a
different opinion you say okay good luck
I respect your opinion you have the
right to have a different opinion and
that's it I'm not gonna attempt to
change your opinion
yeah so there are people I see I mean I
see comments every day that that
contradict me that say that I am wrong
I'm stupid I'm foolish you're wrong
you're this you don't argue with these
people it's fine you have a different
opinion I respect that
so this channel is not for everybody
obviously it's not for people who it's
it's for see even
I have been mentally colonized
before 2016 I used to believe in the
Aryan Invasion Theory I used to believe
it
and I used to get really annoyed with
people who
put forth a different opinion I said
that why do you have to challenge
everything
So I myself was like that it's only when
I went down to Brass tax and I looked at
the primary evidence instead of reading
books I went and looked at the actual
research that's when I realized that
they are this is actually true the iron
invention theory is completely false so
I thankfully I believe I have an open
mind I am open to changing my mind when
I find new evidence and new data that
shows me a different perspective so it's
about having an open mind so if you find
a mentally coronased person who is
willing to engage in a constructive
interaction debate whatever
and who is open-minded and who is
capable of constructive thinking then
you can engage them in conversation
dialogue debate whatever you want to
call it but there will be people who
will just argue for the sake of arguing
they will not even listen to
facts data even if you show them all the
facts they will say you're wrong
and they will argue on the basis of
opinions and other and emotions so see
the so you don't deal with the people
you don't argue with them it's a waste
of energy and time to argue with people
with most people I would say with 99 of
people it's a waste of time to argue
with them you know especially when they
come with this attitude and then this
this dogmatic
uh you know system belief system
so the main thing is you you don't deal
with them you don't argue with them
don't don't waste your time arguing with
people
uh
Asterix what's the stinting Tintin I
think both are fun
whoa the French almost scored but the
goalkeeper saved Argentina
wow that was close boom
all right great so it's still two two uh
Aesthetics versus Tintin uh I think
Tintin was a Belgian comic
gossini and uderzo
were the creators of Tintin I really
enjoyed Tintin as a kid As I Grew Older
I realized that there is there are
elements of Belgian colonialism
attitudes and all that in Tintin later
some of the books
some of the Tintin comics were
you know kind of edited to to take that
out especially Tintin in Congo for
instance
uh for Belgium has a horrific Colonial
record in in the Congo region for for
instance if you don't know yeah so so
otherwise you know Tintin was fun as a
kid for me to read and in some cases it
was actually good for instance there is
this uh this one episode or one book you
know Tintin book I think it's the Costa
Fury Emerald if I'm not mistaken in
which
is it the cost of your Emerald or is it
the calculus Affair I'm not sure which
one it is but uh
in which they have portrayed romanis as
good people actually and they've kind of
uh called out the anti-romani racism
that the Europeans have so that's also
something that I noticed
uh so overall I really enjoyed tinted as
a kid Asterix was fun
Asterix is a French comic it's it's from
the Roman times
his great partner the names are really
funny the the goalish names and the
Gothic names and the Roman names there's
this guy called vital statistics
there is this the dog's name is
dogmatics
really funny and I I read the original
uh
the original uh comics in in French as a
kid
so it was fun it was fun to read and it
it's always portraying the girls the
French as The Underdogs against the
Roman imperialists it's it's fun to read
uh the the great fight in Caesar's gift
so yeah these are two comic book series
that I really enjoyed as a kid did I
read anything else I think I read Lucky
Luke
I don't think anyone knows about Lucky
Luke in India so that's something I read
I also read the rip Kirby from I don't
know it's very old there are some comic
books that I read it was fun fun to
watch yeah
fun to read sorry
um favorite cricket match there have
been many cricket matches the favorite
series or the last two Series in
Australia when we when India defeated
Australia in Australia twice in a row
that was fun too fun to watch uh from
the older series I think
wow Messi nearly scored
good job the goalkeeper
um the 2001 Series against Australia in
which India came back from 1-0 down and
a follow-on down and we defeated
Australia 2-1 in a three-match series
it was all turned around with the help
of dravid in lakshman that enormous
partnership lakshman scored 281
it kind of broke the mental colonization
shackles of Indians the inferiority
complex under the leadership of the
great sourav Ganguly so that's one of
the favorite series
favorite matches the World Cup matches
against Pakistan the 92 one I watched it
was good to watch I think I watched some
of it I was not allowed to watch the
whole of it but yeah
India defeated Pakistan in that I I
think I watched the last part
I was supposed to study
uh I remember srinath yorked Myan dad
the ball was so fast before the bat
comes down the ball was into the stumps
it was fun to watch that yeah so
there are lots of matches I can talk
about very good matches uh the hero cup
1992 hero cup uh final against the West
Indies took six for 12. and many more
recent matches the 2007 uh T20 World Cup
final the semi-final also
the match against England
the the the miss baula incident the
scoop shot that he tried to play against
joginder Sharma
it was his last International match but
in his last ball in an international
cricket but he got the most important
Wicket you know
and so on there are many many great
matches the 2011 World Cup final bone is
six let's sealed the deal for for India
so many more
cast of your Emerald yes sir so you've
read it huh
good good
Argentina you're gonna do it
not gonna do it
I think it's time for extra time now
that's it here we are
it's 2-2 at the end of
full time
Roti it's it's a personal choice
you get protein from Dal and chaval Roti
is your carbohydrate so it's a full meal
yeah and hopefully you will add some
vegetable ingredients to your Dal like
you know tomatoes and and onion and
garlic ginger coriander maybe
they'll give you a full meal it's a
personal choice whether you want to eat
Dal chaval or Dal Roti or maybe both why
not
Roti chawal both are good sources of
carbohydrates
a good source of good sources of energy
uh all right all right so we are at the
end of full time it's it's a stalemate
to do so we're gonna have extra time
so we'll see
good match good match it's it's going
better than we expected yeah
uh
says do you think George R.R Martin will
ever release the Winds of Winter uh the
guy takes his time so we don't know if
he does great
yep
okay I seem to have missed you know I if
I speak for 17 hours I will I will
remember everything and I will not miss
anything
yeah yeah murlidering was a wonderful
incredible bowler
he you know was actually
a leg spinner you know what leg spin
leg spin is when you do this this
because as this he had this incredible
flexibility in his wrist and some
some bone defect in his arm which gave
him this this
permanent Bend in his arm so because of
that structural
uniqueness of his arm he was able to
bowl that way and he used to bowl these
leg Spinners but they used to come out
of spinners and he had this huge turn
and obviously he's the great highest
Wicket taker in test match cricket I
think 800 wickets yeah so yes morally is
I think he's an Indian citizen is it Sri
Lankan citizen I'm not sure maybe dual
citizen if it's allowed in some cases I
think he lives in Chennai
maybe maybe the greatest
bowler of all time at least if you talk
about spin Bowlers I would say there are
two great spin Ballers the two greatest
are morally and chain one
I really enjoyed Shane Moon watching
Shane won more
because I at one point in time I myself
wasn't like spinner as a kid before I
grew taller taller I was a leg spinner
so yeah
so Morley and chain one both have the
same wrist spinning action but yeah so
uh dhyanjan hoki of course one of the
greatest players of all time Sean
Pollock is is okay he's okay he's
definitely one of the great all-rounders
Jacques Calis I would say is a greater
all-rounder than Sean Pollock
maybe Ashwin not maybe 100 Ashwin is
greater than front Pollock as an
all-rounder
Ashwin is greater than wasimakram as an
non-rounder Ashwin Ashwin if you look at
his record as an all-rounder in test
match cricket it is greater than that of
Imran Khan the former prime minister of
Pakistan yeah
so yeah that's the deal uh batsman yeah
yes great batsman great record
statistically the greatest ever
for sure
I can give you 500 more names Mission
Singh baby
Raju if you remember the guy
like I've spoken of before Zahir Khan
Great left arm baseballer Java girl
srinath come on you want to talk about
other countries uh
what about uh
Dale Stein Dale Stein was a great boy he
recently retired great bowler what about
Mornay more kill
Malcolm Marshall
Joel Garner
Dennis Lilly I can give you 500 more
names I'm not and if I don't give a
certain name you'll say I've missed it
come on it's not like that it doesn't
work like that
yeah
um
have I heard interstellar's theme song I
obviously have heard it it's beautiful
I'm a huge music fan I've been a kind of
an amateur musician in the past I'm no
longer one I've not picked up the guitar
in years I still have it somewhere I
think it needs a new set of strings no
time yeah but yes yeah a huge huge fan
of music I love music
I I love
weird music I mean you would call it
weird music very I have a very eclectic
taste in music and in literature in
almost everything
for instance I I really like the music
of Mali Western Africa
western Africa is actually the the
birthplace of the Blues blues music no
so artists like Ali farkature view
uh when you may not have heard of any of
these people but that music is wonderful
I like the music of Ethiopia
it's your jazz jazz music from Ethiopia
you should try it out go to YouTube and
search for ethio jazz
e-t-h-i-o-e-t-o jazz wonderful very
interesting music that comes out of
Africa I even like the music that comes
from Somalia
that sounds kind of Indian you know you
can see there's a there's an
undercurrent of Indian influence in the
music of Somalia
the over current if you were to call it
that is is Arabic but the undercurrent
is Indian there's a much deeper layer of
Indian influence in Somali music in
eastern African music in the music of
Kenya Kenya has good music
I think every every culture has a
wonderful music musical tradition
sometimes it may take some time to get
used to it you know if you've never
heard before but you you listen to it a
few times it's it's interesting so I
look for music from all kinds of places
I listen to a lot of Celtic folk music
Celtic harp and uh you know other
instruments as well
and like you say uh interstellar's theme
song Wonderful
wonderful I really like it
views on Harry Potter
Harry Potter is cast East
it's got a four level caste system
Gryffindor Slytherin
Ravenclaw
Hufflepuff
what is what what is that if not a caste
system and they even have the outcasts
the
the elves right
and they have this this this
what blood traitors
and mud Bloods
what did what did she do JK Rowling
um I think I've read all the books
actually I have read all of them
uh they don't they're not bad
they're actually quite interesting I
would not spend the time and read seven
books I did that more than 10 years ago
but I did read all the books they were
good books but over time you kind of see
the undercurrents where does where does
all this come from
so it's interesting that JK Rowling
created and created a four four level
cast system in in her in her mythology
in her book
you know interesting
but yeah it was it was it was uh fun to
read more than watch
even the movies were okay I guess even
I've seen the movies too I'm sure
this is a good question is Kachi spoken
in Balochistan
I'm not sure
but it's possible
because crutch is right next to bologism
catch is next to send and send this next
to Balochistan there was a time when
Balochi was the primary language in
Karachi
Karachi yeah
are you know more or less
neighboring regions of India
temporarily Pakistan we know that okay
no need to remind me but yeah you know
what I mean yes
so yeah it's a good question but I don't
have any sources in biology sun today I
don't know how it is today you know
there's been a lot of social engineering
and ethnic cleansing in Pakistan after
1947. so I'm not sure what the situation
is now but Balochistan historically I'm
sure Kachi would have been spoken in the
past or there yeah
um
what's the most interesting thing about
quantum mechanics the most interesting
thing about quantum mechanics is that we
don't quite understand what it's trying
to tell us there are various
interpretations of quantum mechanics
yeah and they don't agree with each
other
and there is something hidden
we don't quite know what it is and
that's a big mystery we don't quite
understand what causes collapse the the
collapse of the wave function
we don't know the role that
Consciousness may or may not play in
this uh does it lead to parallel
universes in many worlds interpretation
which is a very serious and highly
regarded except uh interpretation of
quantum mechanics lots of physicists
actually
a
are on the side of the many worlds
interpretation
what exactly is entanglement how does it
work there are lots of mysteries it's so
mysterious and it's the it's where our
our world Universe comes from
everything all of this is quantum
mechanical
yeah quantum mechanics is at the heart
of everything in the world and we don't
understand it there is something
there is more than something that we
don't quite understand we know how to
use the equations we know how to
calculate things we know how to use
quantum mechanics as the basis of
various Technologies this broadcast this
telecast would not be happening without
Quantum without technology technologies
that are based in quantum mechanics yeah
and yet we don't we know how to use it
but we don't know what it's telling us
you know
so yeah that's what makes it so
interesting so fascinating
right
how do I rate sigur Ros sigur Ros is a
Nordic
band alternative rock or something
um
there are elements of folk also to it if
I'm not mistaken I I do remember
listening to their music at some point
in time
so yeah it doesn't it's not quite
ringing a bell bell exactly what the
genre of music is I do remember that I
kind of liked it yeah but I haven't
really gone deep into that music so yeah
I'm definitely aware of it
um
right uh Miss You mbappe is kind of
injured on the ground on the ground yes
he's awaiting some treatment
you eat kachita belly I must have eaten
it in the past but uh not a regular it's
been many years since I may have tasted
it yeah but I have certainly eaten eat
it I have eaten it yes
I have eaten it Django Unchained I think
I've watched the movie uh it was a good
reasonably good movie
um yeah so I I have watched it
I was it Quentin Tarantino
I like Tarantino's movies very very
interesting movies very stylistic and
obviously there is a
he has he creates this alternative
history stories and all that
and some of the movies are kind of
ridiculous at times but always fun to
watch always fun to watch
uh Argentina you're gonna do something
nah
okay so yeah Django Unchained I have
watched
um
no no no no that is that is wrong
grammar it is heated heated I have not
eaten please please please please I I my
grammar is perfect the correct term is
heated you know how do you say that I
want to make a balloon Bigger
you say I am going to begin it
I'm going to big if I begin fight
it's medium size I want to make it
larger I will say I will big if I am
begin the balloon and when you when the
past tense of eating
of heat is heated not eaten
uh what was the origin of ahora Mazda
India so um
so um is the the primary God in
Zoroastrianism right obviously we know
that a Zoro austrianism by the way is a
polytheistic religion it's not a
monotheistic religion everybody tells
you know most historians will tell you
this most of your history teachers will
tell you this and most people believe
this that Zoroastrianism is the original
monotheistic religion nothing could be
further from the truth Zoroastrianism is
a polytheistic religion they have
multiple levels of divinities all right
uh now what is the origin of ahora Mazda
well
you could consider Zoroastrianism to be
a kind of revisionist version of
Hinduism yeah it it all originates with
with zarathostra
was born I believe in bahalik bulk which
was then a part of India it was part of
bulk is currently a part of Afghanistan
which historically in the old days was
part of India until very until just the
past Millennium or so
and he was born obviously a Hindu
because there was before him there was
no other religion or no other the only
Hinduism
so whatever he came up with emerged out
of the cultural milieu
that he was raised in
and if you look at zoro's feminism it's
merely an inversion of Hinduism
so the Devas are portrayed as bad guys
and the Asura supported is good guys
in in what we call Hinduism the Devas
are the good guys and the asuras have
some somewhat negative connotations yeah
has essentially inverted that that's
more or less it and ahura Mazda is the
primary Divinity so so all of this
originates out of Hinduism most of the
of most of these are Australian rituals
rights Traditions practices and in
philosophy most of it is is rooted in
the old Vedic religion of India
okay nothing else has happened thus far
the French have received a corner
a corner so let's see what they will do
from that
okay
says what made
a great leader how does he compare to
someone like them shopping
well then shopping for for one for for
starters was never a soldier
link shopping was an administrator he
was a politician
was primarily a soldier a war fighter
he was a leader of men in battle he
faced bullets he had bullets fly past
him I'm sure he was injured on occasion
he saw everything you can ever possibly
witness on a field of battle
he faced death on a routine basis
yeah any anyone he succeeded and he put
his life in everything on the line in
the Turkish war of independence yeah in
the 19 early 1920s
he stood up to the European powers he
stood up to the ottoman Sultan and he
defeated them all and he won
Independence for turkey for for turkey
so just one guy did this through his
strength of character's strength of
personality and strength of leadership
so he was a soldier he was a warrior he
was a leader General whatever you would
call him yeah and then once he took off
his uniform after the Turkish war of
independence he never wore the uniform
again and then he was the leader of the
country administrator yeah
so he essentially played two roles in
his lifetime one was that of a soldier
and second that of the leader of his
Nation the father of his Nation
so that's what made Arthur a great
leader was he a brutal guy or he was a
dictator
he ensured that he was a dictator he
ensured that all his opposition was
crushed
that's what you got to do
and that's what it did
and he obviously
dragged turkey forcibly out of the 19th
century and into the modernity of the
20th century he created turkey as a
modern Progressive science you know
scientific oriented all that progress
oriented Nation a secular Nation a
secular Nation
but he was not able to turn it into a
democracy maybe he did not want that
so if you look at the history of turkey
after ataturk's death I think it was in
1938 that he died after that it's always
been mostly Army rule yeah nowadays we
have uh quasi-democratic process or
whatever but that's how it is
just one man dragged turkey out of the
Middle Ages and into the 20th century
and one man
gave freedom to Turkey just one man
obviously people fought under him and
they followed orders but it was this one
guy without whom nothing would have
happened
even Winston Churchill's plan in 1915
was it
of
invading turkey
uh the the
Gallipoli Invasion that was foiled only
by one man he went against the orders of
his superiors and he he took certain
decisions that he was not allowed to he
was not supposed to and that's why
that's what saved turkey from the
British and that's what caused this
terrible humiliation
to Winston Churchill so that is what
made other great then Chopin was not a
fighter he was not a soldier
he was a politician what he did is that
he brought China out of the uh he out of
the days of Mao satung
and he brought in progress and modernity
and capitalism
he essentially tried to recreate what uh
Lee Kuan Yew had done in the city-state
of Singapore now it's very easy to
reform a city-state in 20 years you know
and that's what Lee Kuan you you did
within a generation he took Singapore
out of third world status he made it a
first world nation a first world city
state a modern city state in just uh
barely a generation that's what Lee Kuan
Yew did
then shopping tried to do that for China
in enormous Nation yeah the same thing
and he what China is today is largely
because of the process that Deng
shopping set in motion
so you can't quite compare Lee Kuan Yew
to then shopping to Ataturk had a
smaller Nation but it was still the it
was it still both the legacy of the
Ottoman Empire
and he was able to
turn it into a success a reasonably
successful 20th Century Modern
nation-state and it would not have been
possible without so three different
people and they have different legacies
today I think they're trying to erase
the legacy of Ataturk in Turkey
because he essentially tried to
secularize Turkey
he he changed the
the holiday from Friday to Sunday
he banned the Islamic Veil and the
burkha and all that for women
uh
he brought in a uniform civil court in
Turkey
and and lots of these reforms that uh
are now they are trying to undo today
so um
there is in in certain sections I
believe of Turkish Society there is some
kind of dislike or maybe even hatred
foreign but they would not be enjoying
the quality of life and whatever they
have today had he not done the things
that he did yeah so that's a deal
that is the deal
okay
so it's still 2-2
we're almost at the end of extra time
and the argentines almost scored
they did not get a corner they wanted a
corner
so that is ongoing
um
why is temur not praised like chingis
Khan both were step conquerors well
please study history then you will
understand
the move was a genocidal Barbarian
he conquered for the sake of conquering
in the for the sake of killing and for
the sake of plunder
Genghis Khan conquered for very
different reasons
so I'm not gonna see I'm not gonna go
into the details now but uh
Timur was a brutal monstrous
bloodthirsty genocidal Barbarian
triggers Khan was not they say that
changes can't cause the deaths of God I
don't know how many million people uh I
would like to see the primary sources on
which that these these figures are based
they say that changes can't kill let's
say 30 million people or something
yeah
um
if you see even if we were to take that
as as a fact let's say that is correct
that maybe he killed it's a 30 billion
people have you seen the amount of
territory in square kilometers that he
conquered if you take the number of
deaths divided by divided by the the
territory then you will come to a figure
of how many people died during the
conquest of the conquests of Genghis
Khan per square kilometer I promise you
it's going to be less than the number of
people per square kilometer who died in
the U.S invasion of Iraq
in the second world war in the
Bangladesh War which Pakistan uh created
yeah the genocide they did and many
other Wars I can guarantee
that the per square kilometer death
death death toll in the conquest of
Genghis Khan was lower than all these
modern campaigns
so it's just you know it's just a
eurocentric perspective of demonizing
in non-abrahamic conqueror
okay
abrahamic warlord he was abrahamic
warlord
um so yeah Timur was a brutal Barbarian
and I you can now forget him for what he
did in Iran in Persia and in India even
the Persians hate him
the persons despise them or there must
be a reason for that yeah
it was a brutal Barbarian brute monster
and he killed a hundred thousand
innocent men women and children in one
day in Delhi
yeah so let's not equate apples with
oranges and you know if you say I'm
biased because he because stringist Khan
did not hurt India well I am biased deal
with it
I'm gonna see it from my perspective
that's how it is
all right
let's see what other some questions are
being repeated so I will not take those
why does why isn't Putin using nukes it
would be fun uh I am I expect your 12 or
13 years old which is why you ask this
question
right
uh so we are still at 2-2 in the final
will Argentina or France prevail
thus far it's still a tie
um
it's a very very very complex topic so
yeah uh
I was about to click on something else
and
I got a different question
my opinion
when he started his career as a great
leader he's one of the greatest Kings
and leaders India has ever seen he was
not a 50 year old man what is Akshay
Kumar's age he's clearly above 50. why
can't they find a younger actor to
portray the young shivaji Maharaj
I don't understand these things you know
that's that's that's the criticism
everybody has that why do they have to
why can't they discover young Talent if
you look at the West
they keep on unearthing new Talent
whenever there's a new series that comes
up they find new actors and actresses to
portray the rules they actually have
screen tests and all that in the case of
Bollywood it's the same old same old
every time all the time it's tiresome to
see the same faces I do not want to see
the same old tired face playing
portraying the role of the Great
leader the great warrior the great king
Maharaj
so I am going to give it a Miss I'm not
watching the series or movie or whatever
it is that's coming out
I I would like somebody else to do it
why can't the Marathi film industry
do it
their own version of the life and career
of the Great chatrapati shivaji Maharaj
may be at 10 part series one hour one
hour per episode why not that way why do
we need a Bollywood actor to portray the
great man I don't understand
no goal still 2-2
okay it's it's still going on
another
I think Argentina have scored
is it the case
is it the case I think it is yeah baby
Argentina has scored it's 3-2
I'm waiting for the confirmation on the
scorecard it still says 2-2 on the
scorecard
but the ball certainly crossed the line
it went inside the net
and Monsieur Griezmann is sitting very
pensively he's not very happy
uh let us see it is still saying two two
but I look I think that the ball went
into the net
let us see let us see I'm gonna I'm
watching the replay it's not offside for
sure
and the ball is buried and yes it's it's
a goal it's three two
it's it's definitely three two
uh suhani says it's three two I agree ah
now it says three two on the scorecard
so it looks like Argentina May once
again have the upper hand
yes it looks like there's still how many
minutes to go I think 10 minutes to go
roughly
so still 10 minutes the French still
have some time in which they can make a
comeback
we shall see
uh what exactly is long boarding
longboarding is a sport I think
let me just go do a Google search am I
Oh you mean yeah yeah
longboarding uh I am familiar with the
shorter uh skateboard
longboarding is a longer version of that
yeah so I've never done that
I've done uh briefly I've done briefly
ice skating it's it's not hard uh you
know the professional ice skaters they
use these these thin blades steel blades
or whatever metal it is uh as a beginner
you are given a thicker blade you know a
thicker plastic blade
so I think the first time I tried it it
took me about 15-20 minutes to get to
get the hang of it you know you fall and
stumble a few times you should wear a
jeans or something it's quite cold and
then you slice you you get the bearings
you get the balance and all so I have
done ice skating a few times as a kid a
long long long time ago it was fun
okay this question I've got a million
times best books and more year rajput
maratha Empire
rajput maratha Empire
um most of the knowledge I have acquired
about the more years about the rajputs
ETC is is been through uh not through
books
through research articles Journal
articles all that
uh uh
uh there are very few books written
about rajputs uh I I'm sure there's a
there's this book about uh
the great king prithviraj Johan authored
by virendra Singh rathore I think he no
I don't think I know that he he has been
on my podcast a couple of times so
that's one but uh as such our wonderful
historians have not written much about
the rajputs
uh there are books about the marathas
but I haven't read those I I I am not
that
uh I have not studied maratha history in
that that much depth actually you know
that's something I need to rectify in
the future I will read more about it and
um so that's the case so
to answer your question I don't have
recommendations
I don't actually have recommendations uh
like I said our historians have not
really paid much attention to the
history of the rajputs and if for for
the for the maurians I think you can
read the books of RC majumdar Etc
because no new research has been done in
the past Century
no new archaeological work has been done
in the roughly in roughly the past
Century that brings new facts to light
about the maurians so whatever was
written out 70 80 years ago it's still
it's still valid so maybe you should
read the books of RC majumdar
descended of rigvedic Clans says
recently some Soma evidence was found in
in this Valley Civilization
4500 BC years old spoked wheel was also
found uh yeah that's good the Soma
evidence is the interpretation of the
bull or some animal is soma a Soma
that's what it was uh so yeah I I still
haven't studied that in detail what new
uh evidence seems to have been found
spoked whales I would not be surprised
if they find more evidence of spoked
wheels and all that so yeah as and when
new evidence comes out new facts come
out we will I will certainly study it
and if if it is something significant I
will certainly speak about it over here
but I'm aware of of this yeah
um
once again questions about Chess
I already answered
same question a bit earlier about Chess
my views on Kundalini Yoga I don't know
much about Kundalini Yoga I have never
done it myself practice it myself I am
myself not even very clear about what
Kundalini is it's it's a form of energy
it is said and all
um
spoke about it briefly Kundalini but not
in great depth because we do not go into
that was not the subject of the
discussion
so
yeah so yeah so I'm not a very much of
an expert or even slightly of an expert
about this
okay
first chakra
views on Vikings you mean the series or
the people the people are the old Nordic
people uh the ancestors of today's the
other people of of
modern day Sweden Denmark and Norway not
Finland Sweden Denmark Norway their
ancestors for the Vikings there were
these uh
the polytheistic Europeans or they
followed the old
uh Indo-European religion culture
whatever yeah they had this this
polytheistic Pantheon of gods the
primary most powerful God was Thor which
is the Nordic version of the god Indra
and the story of Indra and Thor is the
same yeah moral is the same
um Thunder God Hammer God who defeats a
great sea serpent in the case of Indra
it is vritra in the case of Thor it is
your mungunder the great sea serpent and
so on so yeah there were conquerors they
were they were looters pillagers they
they launched wave after wave of
expedition
on on Europe Expeditions on Europe
primarily England
or Northern England and also France
um
they conquered England lots of people in
northern England they have Viking
ancestry Nordic ancestry they conquered
France the French King offered a big
chunk of France to the leader of the
Vikings Rollo roll of the Viking and
Rolo became the first book of Normandy
and his great great grandson was William
who was called Guillaume the bastard
they called him William the bastard
because his his father was not married
to his mother yeah he was an
illegitimate son but he went on to
become William the Conqueror who
conquered England the last king the last
Invader to successfully conquer England
in the year one zero six six
and so yeah all that yeah so that's
briefly about the Vikings yeah
oh
okay
penalty do we have penalty
that would be fun ah we may have a
penalty
somebody's elbow
we have a penalty France has got a
penalty would you believe it
twists and turns
good for the movies
yes I have watched The Godfather movies
part one and part two was wonderful part
three yeah not so good
part two may be the greatest God for the
movie of them all you know Al Pacino's
coming of age
the the uh the coming of Ages are
actually in part one part two is more
about the backstory of the original
Godfather
um and so on
so yeah great movies great movies
certainly something you can watch
repeatedly like not every day but you
know once a couple of years it's always
good to watch it
okay mbappe is going to take the penalty
let us see what happens is it gonna
score
my goodness
what a match what a match
is it gonna be three three
let us see here we go here we go
it is three three
wonderful wonderful
goal Anisha says three three wonderful
so this looks like a classic one of the
classic World Cup final matches
uh
did Castro really survive 600 attempts
assassination attempts I think there is
a little bit of Mythology that's been
built around him I'm sure he must have
survived lots of assassination attempts
after all the Americans wanted him dead
so it is possible I'm not sure what the
exact number is but yes he did survive
many assassination attempts
uh favorite self-help book I can't think
of any I don't really read self-help
books I've tried reading some but it's
uh it's it's not it's nearly never
really appealed to me
okay do we have some other interesting
questions looks like I'm very tired do I
look extremely tired have I been lifting
weights running a marathon no no I'm I'm
good I'm good
I'm good
Naruto series I have not watched Naruto
I hear the kids love it
I have not watched Naruto
but it seems to be a very popular uh
enemy right and there are like two three
different iterations or versions of
Naruto
and uh
I'm told there is some there are some
Filler episodes and some episodes that
are kind of boring and all that and
there is a
Fox with nine tails or something and
there is this great Indian Guru who
gives knowledge to Naruto you know yeah
I've heard it's it's fun but I've never
watched it
uh where is it I was clicking on
something else and something else came
up here we are the dictator are you
referring to the movie it's one of the
great movies
uh one of the greatest movie speeches of
all time Charlie Chaplin
and yeah France are saved
the the great dick oh you are referring
to the Sasha Baron Kohan movie The
Dictator that's also a fun movie but not
as great as the original Charlie Charlie
movie The Charlie Chaplin movie was
wonderful show
Naruto and Naruto Shippuden is the best
movie music ever all right all right all
right
uh Shawshank Redemption is yeah it's a
great movie it's a very long movie but I
think it's worth it if you have the
patience to watch a three hour plus
movie I think it's three hour plus if
I'm not mistaken once again I watched it
a long time ago it's it's a it's a great
movie yeah
huh
should India replace its capital city
Delhi is polluted and congested maybe
it's not a bad idea you know there are
many people there are many people who
said that Delhi is cursed it's got bad
luck it's had so many terrible events
the the the massacre at the hands of
Timur the Barbarian yeah
uh and uh what happened to him
people say it's been cursed since the
days of indepth you know
it's it's brought with it bad luck a lot
of bad luck uh people say if you look at
the track record of various capitals
then uh
then
pay shower in mathura our great capitals
uh during the time during the time of
the kushan empire
the kanishka the great of a great
emperor had two capitals two main
capitals the Western Capital was
Peshawar purushpur it was called at the
time of pushkilawati and the Eastern
Capital was mathura
so those two were good capitals maybe we
should bring Peshawar back as the
capital of India but it's too far to the
west of India isn't it I mean
temporarily part of Pakistan but you
know what we mean there or maybe partly
Putra it was a great Capital it was the
capital of the maurians it was the
capital of the shunga Empire it was the
capital of the Gupta Empire as well so
maybe we should bring
partly Putra back as capital it's now
called Patna maybe we should rename it
to the original name partly Putra
um or maybe we should create a whole new
capital somewhere more centrally located
perhaps
um so yeah maybe it's not a bad idea to
get also the new capital because Delhi
is definitely congested there's a lot of
pollution especially in Winter because
of what happens in neighboring states
this double burning they call it yeah
so maybe it's it's not it's not a bad
idea maybe
right so it's still three three and
we're about
to
maybe enter a penalty shootout
maybe ujjain was a great capital for
some some period of time in India ujjain
was the city of the Indian Meridian
oopsie baby
Argentina is trying for sure and yeah
okay
NADA she says CIA director Praises our
PM or Russia I am confused see if you
pay attention to people's words you will
always be confused
that's why I keep repeating I don't know
how many times I must have repeated
myself
don't pay attention to people's words
just look at their actions
if you will pay attention to words
you'll be confused throughout your life
and that's what I'm seeing here it
doesn't matter what the CIA director
said
oh man how did France miss that they had
a golden opportunity
only the goalkeeper to beat
ma'am
now Argentina is in the Box
and they don't score
so yeah see listen please stop paying
attention to people's words
some people are easy to flatter
some people love flattery it is very
easy to mislead them with words so yeah
the the Americans know that historically
Indians have been very easy to mislead
and fool say nice words give some nice
treatment but don't give anything of
substance
that work with people like the great
magnificent Mr nehru and all that but it
won't work today
it will not work today let them praise
matters not
so words don't matter please stop being
confused
three time zones for India is what
project Heisenberg asks I think it's not
a bad idea
uh I think even during the British times
Chennai which was then called Madras had
a different time zone than Mumbai
good God mbappe
now Chennai was about 30 minutes
ahead of Mumbai during British times if
I am not mistaken yeah
and India is such a vast
geographical region if you are in let's
say Manipur or on nagaland or whatever
in the Far East of India the sun rises
before 5 a.m why should it be that way
so I think Eastern India and Western
India should be in different time zones
maybe three time zones makes sense for
India and I don't think it will cause a
lot of confusion even the Chinese are
single time zone which makes no sense
whatsoever but that's how it is all
right it's full time even after extra
time three three what a match we are
going into a penalty shootout
all right all the best both teams
so the argentines succeeded in once
again allowing the opposition to wipe
out a 2-0 advantage
but yeah they are still holding form at
three three I have not watched get out
I'm not even aware of the movie
uh
um how to develop a good work ethic you
have to focus on routine routine is
boring especially for people who are
creative but you need a routine
so uh it's something you develop over
time it's like a muscle you know you
need some mental strength some
determination some willpower but also
you need to have a set routine if you
develop a set routine which is going to
give you the the right kind of output
then that will help you develop a good
work ethic
yeah it's not about motivation it's
about creating a system
motivation will bring you nowhere
motivation is for emotional people
people who are driven by mood and moods
and emotions
you can watch a motivational video it
will give you a high for 30 minutes or
one hour and then you go back to the
ground state and then what
so success is not about motivation
success is about creating the right
system that will give you the right work
ethic yeah so you need to have a system
in which you wake up at a certain time
you eat a certain kind of food at the
certain time and so and so time to so
and so time you do a certain kind of
activity and so on if you stick to that
you will automatically have a good at
work ethic
yeah and obviously the work that you are
doing should be something that interests
you and something that you enjoy
sometimes it it can even be something
that you don't ensure but you have to do
but in in that case even in that case if
you have a rights if you have the right
system then that will give you
a good work ethic discipline comes from
having the right system and following
the right system
all right
okay
will Elon Musk succeed in colonizing
colonizing Mars
our time will tell us he already has the
technology yeah uh he has built the the
Starship rocket uh it's not been tested
fully yet it's not gotten gone into
Earth orbit or moon orbit or something
it's the rocket that is supposed to take
him take people take humans to moon to
the Moon
so it's being tested you know they are
constantly testing
their systems their Rockets their
engines and all that
so that's how you you ensure that the
system works because when you have a
rocket like the Starship that they are
building you're gonna put like 50 people
or 100 people on board and you don't
want that rocket to fail
that would be a disaster you know uh if
if you have like three people on a
rocket and the rocket fails and the
people for whatever reason lose their
life life it is tragic
but it's not something that is as bad as
losing 50 people so it's gonna be
something that they're gonna have to
take be very careful about
but I don't see why you should not
succeed in colonizing Mars I mean at
least putting human shoes human feet on
Mars it should happen I would say the
next 10 to 20 years for sure
and I hope there are no you know
accidents along the way
so here we are
we are in a penalty shootout
and
it's gonna be fun
so who's taking it first
okay the two goalkeepers are shaking
hands
wishing each other all the best
that's fine
okay how to become a tyrant Netflix I've
not seen that no
um Twilight Saga I think I saw the first
movie in the Twilight Saga it was okay
it was okay very kind of boring
so I do not watch any of the other
movies I watched the first one out of
curiosity and then I decided not to
watch
the other ones
okay
we'll take the first one
and it's 1-0 to France okay good
mbappe
so France are going first which means
the the argentines are under more
pressure
the goalkeeper got his hands to it but
it still went in
uh
interesting question Sons of Anarchy I
have watched it I thought it was great
it was kind of dark and at the end it
was very dark and kind of sad but
overall a great series
I watched many years ago
great series
uh money Heist and I have not watched it
okay Messi is gonna take it now
big responsibility
and oh we scored
one one
Messi always takes the gentlest of all
penalties but and the goalkeeper was
almost able to make it
but yeah it went in so yeah it's one one
how to read effectively and to have a
memory retention like me
uh I I don't know I don't know if
there's anything special or different
about me My Philosophy when I read
something is that it is all right to
forget everything you're reading in case
it doesn't interest you
so I give myself permission to forget
everything if I read a book and I
remember nothing after afterwards it's
fine I don't care oh my goodness
other thing I have saved a penalty it is
a disaster for France
and the Argentine goalkeeper is all
pumped up
so you know um
if you go in
into reading a book with the pressure
that you have to memorize and remember
everything it's going to be very
counterproductive
I go in I I look at every book in in the
way that you know it's it's okay to not
even finish the book it's okay to start
in the middle if I find if I look at the
chapters and I find something that's
pertinent to what I'm looking for or
something that interests me and maybe if
I find that chapter good then I'll read
the whole book or maybe not and it's
okay to forget things if they're not
interesting that's how I do it that's
mainly why I remember things
ah Argentina have scored so now we are
two one up
I think
vamos vamanos Argentina yes
so now France are under pressure
France are under pressure
um
saurabh says is Panini the greatest of
all time he's definitely the father of
linguistics and maybe his
possibly the greatest human achievement
of all time of all
all history of mankind possibly quite
possibly it's an incredible achievement
a complete algorithmic grammar of a for
a language it's like you've created
a machine
an algorithmic machine that will give
you the right language Sanskrit you know
for Sanskrit okay
let's see
France with the score oh my God fans are
done almost done second penalty missed
this went this one went went wide of the
post
this is the disaster for France who is
this guy
um
that is terrible
okay okay
and the Argentine goalkeeper is very
happy very pleased with himself so it's
2-1
and now Argentina are gonna take the
next penalty kick why are there lots of
African players in the European in
European teams because you know the
history of colonization colonialism
um the French especially
France represents Africa today it looks
like
Argentina have scored again it's 3-1
it's 3-1 it's almost almost done
almost done
almost there
Now France have no option but to score
they have no option but to score
otherwise it's done
um
let us see
is it possible for AI to get
Consciousness I think it's uh unlikely
that AI will ever become conscious and
if you want to go deeper into it please
watch my latest
a podcast with Dr subashka which was
just two three weeks ago
uh we we discussed this in that
okay France is going to take the next
attempt
and they have scored
uh Colo colomoni I think it was good job
and now
now the French goalkeeper has to save
the next penalty otherwise they're done
otherwise the goose is cooked
favorite programming language for the
longest time to see now it's python yeah
I've used all kinds of from programming
language languages but never Java
uh yeah
will I see Shark Tank India season two
I've not even seen season one
I've seen the American Shark Tank really
interesting the old Seasons nowadays
it's kind of is boring you see because
of various reasons
so I've not seen the Indian Shark Tank
season one I heard it was good
reasonably good which is good but I've
not seen it
let's see now Argentina have won the
World Cup if I'm not mistaken yeah
shouts off
Argentina are the new Champions good for
them good for Messi I'm happy for Messi
I don't have any other special
preference for any nation which is not
mine
but I like Messi so for that reason I'm
glad to see Argentina win
A fitting end
to Messi's great career there was the
one thing that was missing for him
and I am sure lots of people will be
pleased for him I'm pleased for him it's
a win for
it's a win for football yeah yeah I I
definitely agree
uh
good match really good match to watch
2-0 then two two then three two then
three three
and then
my
my views on puto's latest stupidity
the guy's an idiot
come on he's see
he's not a diplomat first of all he is
not even a proper politician he's a
dynast
he is in politics and he is at whatever
position he is in because of his mom
his mom is boy
his surname should be zardari actually
because in the subcontinent in worldwide
we typically historically have had the
patrilineal system
so according to his own culture
his surname should be uh bilaval zardari
but he calls himself because his mother
was the former prime minister Pakistan
right
um so that that's beside the point but
so the thing is that he's a dynast he's
not even a competent politician yeah
he can't he can't win an election on his
own
he has this Aura in in this shadow of
his mother over himself and uh he's not
even a qualified Diplomat a career
Diplomat or any he doesn't have any
diplomatic credentials or whatever yeah
so he has spoken the way an idiot would
speak so why do we have to pay a lot of
attention to it
it's it's I I don't even know what he
said okay by the way I've not listened
to his comments I've not heard his
comments I have not read a transcript of
what he said it up case like he said
something insulting to our prime
minister well you know when you walk on
the street and a dog barks at you will
you take it as a personal insult you
will disregard it right
yes so we've got to disregard these
things these people don't matter he's a
nobody he is a nobody that's what he is
so it's fine
if I remember correctly uh Imran Khan
when he was prime minister
he was very frustrated and upset that Mr
Modi never ever
that Mr Modi never had a telephone
conversation with him or whatever you
know he completely ignored him but Imran
Khan never descended to the such a level
of using insulting or abusive or or you
know
unacceptable language for the leader of
a Nation Imran Khan never did that as
far as I remember in this immature
person beloved has gone ahead and said
something stupid
just disregard it the way you would
disregard a stray dog barking at you for
whatever reason you just ignore it same
way yeah
so yes Argentina and Messi the god very
happy good for him India only says
history has been created for Messi I
agree it's the cherry on top of a great
career
good for him good for him very happy to
see that
and he is now Overjoyed in tears
and that's fine
foreign
's mother also spewed a huge amount of
Venom and tried terrorism and Hindu
genocide same for zulfikar what's the
surprise here absolutely no surprise and
totally right
below's mother Benazir was a virulent
indophobe
um
which is watching anyway yeah was the
mother of the Taliban yeah and uh she
was very much anti-india deeply this
hatred and the bilal's father also was
was very
hateful towards India despite apparently
being a rajput or something yeah rajput
Buddhas are Sindhi rajputs if I'm not
mistaken I may be wrong but that's the
impression that I get get that butos are
of rajput lineage in converted
dashboards so it's strange to see all
this yeah but it's okay it's it's not
surprising it's not surprising at all
okay
yes Argentina one that is right how to
learn a language you mean language how
to learn a language I the the easiest
way to learn a language is to immerse
yourself in an environment where that
language is the primary language that
it's spoken so let's for so for instance
how do you learn French you go to France
and spend a week there not a week there
you spend a month there among people who
speak only French then you have no
option but to find ways to communicate
in only in the for that you to pick up
French if you place yourself in an
environment where you are immersed in
that language then you're going to learn
it very easily otherwise you have to
find the right book or the fire right
the right technique or whatever and
that's a hit and miss kind of thing so
uh the way I learned French was I was
immersed in a French environment so I as
a kid you learn you pick up a language
very fast very rapidly you don't even
realize when you started speaking the
language
as as uh older as you get older it
becomes harder to pick up a language
so either you immerse yourself in that
language and you or you practice it
seven eight nine hours a day or you find
the right program or right book which
can be hit or miss if you get lucky
you'll find the right one otherwise not
that's how it is
anyhow my friends Argentina has one I am
happy to see that uh sorry I'm I'm kind
of sad for France as well they also had
uh
a good team
is good that's what I hear so it's a
good if it's if it's helping you it's
good yeah
the main thing is you should be able to
speak communicate it's one thing to
learn how to read and write but uh
speaking is a whole different thing
okay so we are at the end of The
Telecast and we have crossed three and a
half hours of this live stream so I
think I'm gonna end it today for here I
had picked a whole bunch of questions
from the from the comments but obviously
I'm not going to be able to take them so
maybe in the next episode I'll pick up
some of those questions that you would
ask me this week all right
so um so I'm gonna end it here
thank you very much for for being with
me for for watching the match with me
despite a World Cup match being on and
all yeah
uh last question Million Dollar Baby
I've watched it it was kind of sad but
it was a good movie yeah Clint Eastwood
was a director in one of the
protagonists anyhow so my dear friends
thank you so much
for being on this telecast with me on
the live stream take care and I will see
you in next week's live streams until
then take care take good care of your
health
and see you soon